<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog-daily-listings-rss" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Daily Listings RSS</title>
    <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog-daily-listings-rss</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/feed/blog/white-house" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hola from Cuba: Two Years After Normalizing Relations</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/16/hola-cuba-two-years-after-normalizing-relations</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<strong>Today marks two years from when President Obama announced the normalizing of relations with Cuba. Hear from Julia de la Rosa,&nbsp;a Cuban entrepreneur, on how her life was changed by the President&#039;s actions.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<hr />
<p>
	My name is Julia de la Rosa, and I am a Cuban <em>cuentapropista --</em>&nbsp;or Cuban entrepreneur<em>. </em>Over 20 years ago, my husband and I started&nbsp;our own business in Cuba providing lodging and transportation to visitors in our neighborhood in Havana. Everything about my business was on a very small scale: We had two&nbsp;bedrooms and one&nbsp;old car, and we did almost everything ourselves.</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://medium.com/@rhodes44/charting-a-new-course-with-cuba-two-years-of-progress-a313982284d9#.4crexnbu6">Today marks two years from when the President decided to normalize America&#039;s&nbsp;relationship with my country.</a></p>

<p>
	As a <em>cuentapropista, </em>I watched this historic change help my business grow in ways I would have never expected. The demand for our services dramatically increased with the growing number of visitors, so we had the opportunity to expand. We now run a real bed and breakfast with 10 bedrooms, and have 17 people working with us as we provide services 24 hours a day, seven days a week. Now, we’re starting a small taxi company, as transportation requests have increased -- especially in old, classic cars. Thanks to these new times, we can even come to the U.S. to buy pieces to restore our eight American cars.</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://medium.com/@rhodes44/charting-a-new-course-with-cuba-two-years-of-progress-a313982284d9#.4crexnbu6">And this change has made a difference for Americans, too.</a></p>

<p>
	More than 500,000 Americans visited Cuba last year. Ten U.S. airlines are flying between American and Cuba citizens. And American cruise lines will soon start pulling into our ports. That’s going to mean a lot for Cuba’s development.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	But this new relationship has not only changed my business, it’s changed my life. Like many others Cubans, I have family in the U.S., and thanks to President Obama’s decision to re-establish relations, my biggest dream could finally come true -- to travel to Miami to meet my father&#039;s family. I am incredibly grateful to President Obama for his leadership in forging this historic change for the U.S. and Cuba, and for what it will mean to both the Cuban and American people for generations to come.</p>

<p>
	Hope to see you in Havana soon,</p>

<p>
	Julia de la Rosa</p>

<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 11:44:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/simone-leiro&quot;&gt;Simone Leiro&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-315116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Address: Ensuring a Fair and Competitive Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/16/weekly-address-ensuring-fair-and-competitive-marketplace</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	In this week’s address, President Obama discussed the importance of fair competition in the marketplace. The principle of fair competition isn’t a Democratic or a Republican idea – it’s an American idea. Over the past eight years, the Obama Administration has taken many actions to keep the marketplace fair, including: defending a free, open, and accessible internet; cracking down on conflicts of interest by making sure professionals who give retirement advice do so in the consumer’s best interest; and – just this week – standing up for beef, pork, and poultry growers when they’re treated unfairly. The President believes our free-market economy only works when there’s competition and rules are in place to keep it fair, open, and honest. That’s what this is all about – ensuring that everyone has a chance to compete by leveling the playing field and keeping the rules clear and consistent.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/SZ5UEIC-o28?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/17/weekly-address-ensuring-fair-and-competitive-marketplace">Transcript</a> | <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/videos/2016/December/20161217_Weekly_Address_HD.mp4">MP4</a> | <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/videos/2016/December/20161217_Weekly_Address.mp3">MP3</a></p>

<p>
	<span class="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-green" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/14/three-usda-actions-help-farmers-get-fair-shake-explained" target="_self">Dig Deeper</a></span></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/tanya-somanader&quot;&gt;Tanya Somanader&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-315101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Students at Home</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/16/connecting-students-home</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><em>Ed. note: This was originally <a href="https://medium.com/@SecretaryCastro/connecting-students-at-home-f4684e79360f#.kg2se1n4t">posted</a> by the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</em></p>

<div contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1">
<figure class="image-captioned" data-widget="image"><img alt="Washington, D.C. | Students build personal computers to take home at the Best Buy Teen Tech Center at the Boys &amp; Girls Club of Greater Washington." height="932" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/castro%20photo.jpeg" width="1400" />
<figcaption>Washington, D.C. | Students build personal computers to take home at the Best Buy Teen Tech Center at the Boys &amp; Girls Club of Greater Washington.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>Today, as part of HUD’s <a href="http://connecthome.hud.gov/"><em>ConnectHome initiative</em></a> to bring high-speed internet to low-income households with school-aged children in HUD-assisted housing, T-Mobile, the City of New York, and the New York City Housing Authority (NYCHA) have committed to do their part to close the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/wh_digital_divide_issue_brief.pdf">digital divide</a> in New York. I joined Mayor Bill De Blasio, NYCHA, and T-Mobile executives to announce that 5,000 internet-connected tablets will be given to families with children living in public housing in the Bronx.</p>

<p>We’ve come a long way since July 2015, when President Obama launched&nbsp;<em>ConnectHome&nbsp;</em>1,500 miles away from New York in Choctaw Nation. At the time, President Obama stressed the urgency of closing what’s known as the “homework gap.” It’s the digital divide at home that prevents children from accessing the tools and resources needed to be successful at school. At HUD, we know that in a 21st century global economy, this gap is quickly leaving too many folks behind. High-speed internet access is no longer a luxury — it’s a necessity.</p>

<p>Today’s announcement reflects the promise of&nbsp;<em>ConnectHome</em>&nbsp;by bringing the private and public sectors together to unlock the power of high-speed internet for low-income families. Each tablet has been donated by our latest national stakeholder, T-Mobile, and will be connected to high-speed internet through sharply discounted service paid for by the City of New York. Together, the commitment will have a tremendous impact, opening the doors of opportunity for thousands of deserving kids and families in New York.</p>

<p>It also builds on tremendous collaboration seen in the 28&nbsp;<em>ConnectHome</em>&nbsp;pilot communities across the country. internet Service Providers, including Cox Communications, AT&amp;T, Google Fiber, and Comcast, have each extended free or low-cost internet offers that together reach 43 states and hundreds of thousands of public housing residents. In addition, to ensure that families make the most of their new connections, organizations like EveryoneOn, Boys &amp; Girls Club, College Board, Common Sense Media, Best Buy, and GitHub are providing technical training, digital literacy and college prep programs, and devices for newly connected families. From Rockford, Illinois, to Washington, DC, to Kansas City, Missouri,<em>&nbsp;ConnectHome&nbsp;</em>has spurred new innovations in public-private partnerships that are changing tens of thousands of lives.</p>

<div>
<p class="image-center" data-widget="image"><img alt="ConnectHome Graphic" height="512" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/graphichud.png" width="1024" /></p>
</div>

<p>The federal government has an important role to play in closing the digital divide and creating opportunity for low-income families. Today’s announcement coincides with the completion of two new rules this week that will encourage — and in some cases require — public housing authorities to install high-speed internet infrastructure in new construction and significant rehabilitation projects. And to help communities do more to get kids connected and conduct digital literacy trainings, HUD and the Corporation for National and Community Service (CNCS) will deploy a cohort of AmeriCorps VISTA members to support the&nbsp;<em>ConnectHome</em>&nbsp;Initiative throughout the 28 pilot communities.</p>

<p>Last week, I had the opportunity to meet Hayden Stonebarger, a 14-year-old member of Choctaw Nation who was inspired by President Obama’s challenge. He’s a member of the Choctaw Nation Youth Advisory Board (YAB), an organization of students who strive to make a difference in their community. Through the YAB’s work on the local&nbsp;<em>ConnectHome&nbsp;</em>program, Hayden helps connect the elders of his community to the internet and shows them how to access vital resources like ordering their medicine online. These connections also help to bridge generations by empowering elders to share their life experiences and traditional culture with the students, while providing them a regular visit to look forward to. With help from&nbsp;<em>ConnectHome</em>, Choctaw Nation has been able to offer no-cost internet service and devices to all of its residents living in HUD-assisted housing.</p>

<p>As President Obama has said, programs like&nbsp;<em>ConnectHome</em>&nbsp;work because community leaders, nonprofits, and the private sector are all stepping up to do their part. Success will require everyone to be involved and engaged to ensure a bright future for our children. At HUD, we are proud to answer the President’s call to action to open the doors of opportunity to every American.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 15:49:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/secretary-juli%C3%A1n-castro&quot;&gt;Secretary Julián Castro&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-315046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Hanukkah! Chag Sameach from the White House</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/16/happy-hanukkah-chag-sameach-white-house</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<blockquote class="blockquote-1">
	"I want to say how much Michelle and I appreciate the opportunities to have celebrated so many Hanukkahs with you in the White House ... As many of you know, the name “Hanukkah” comes from the Hebrew word for “dedication.” So we want to thank you again for your dedication to our country, to the historic progress that we’ve made, to the defense of religious freedom in the United States and around the world."</blockquote>

<blockquote class="blockquote-1">
	&nbsp;</blockquote>

<blockquote class="blockquote-1">
	—President Obama at the 2016 Hanukkah celebration&nbsp;</blockquote>

<p>
	<em>&nbsp;</em></p>

<p>
	This week, President and First Lady Obama welcomed&nbsp;more than 1,000 people to join in two White House Hanukkah receptions. Over the past eight years, the President has established a tradition of inviting special guests to light Menorahs of great significance here in the White House.&nbsp;In his final year, the President invited family members of the late Nobel Laureate Elie Wiesel and the late Israeli Prime Minister and President Shimon Peres to join him and the First Lady in celebrating Hanukkah.</p>

<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="President Barack Obama, First Lady Michelle and Rabbi Rachel Isaacs join Chemi Peres and Mika Almog for the menorah lighting during Hanukkah in the East Room of the White House, Dec. 14, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)" height="1334" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/hannukah2.jpg" width="2000" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 2000px;">
		President Barack Obama, First Lady Michelle and Rabbi Rachel Isaacs join Chemi Peres and Mika Almog for the menorah lighting during Hanukkah in the East Room of the White House, Dec. 14, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	<span style="color:rgb(67, 67, 67); font-family:arial,helvetica,nimbus sans l,sans-serif; letter-spacing:0.13px">The Menorah at the first reception was made in kindergarten by Shira Wiesel, the granddaughter of Elie Wiesel.&nbsp;</span>This menorah, though young in shelf life, carries with it the enduring spirit of a people, and of a special family. Elie Wiesel bore witness to one of the darkest chapters in history. He devoted his life to shedding light on the horrors of the Holocaust through acclaimed books like “Night.” Shira’s menorah is more than the innocent creativity of a young school child. It is a testament to the resilience of a family and of a people; it is a flicker of hope in the promise of a new generation; it is the next chapter to the living memorial that was and will forever be Elie Wiesel.</p>

<p class="default">
	<strong><span style="color:rgb(67, 67, 67); font-family:arial,helvetica,nimbus sans l,sans-serif; letter-spacing:0.13px">Watch the President&#039;s remarks at the afternoon Hanukkah reception:&nbsp;</span></strong></p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/M3MNa2U4m0w?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	The Menorah in the second reception belongs to the family of late Israeli President Shimon Peres. During the Holocaust, the menorah was entrusted to a righteous neighbor, who promised to safeguard it in case the family was captured. But one year later, despite the risks, the family quietly locked the doors and closed the windows. They unpacked the menorah and lit the candles to remember and honor the miracle of the Hanukkah story. Days later, German officers raided and burned down the neighbor’s house. All was destroyed, except this menorah.</p>

<p>
	The Walden family survived the raid and the war, and eventually moved to Israel in 1952. Among their meager belongings, they brought their menorah. Two decades later, their son Raphael married Tsvia Peres, the only daughter of Sonia and Shimon Peres, one of Israel’s founding fathers and most prominent lights. The two families have since gathered together every Hanukkah to light this menorah and recall the miracle of its existence and the Jewish people’s continued survival.</p>

<p>
	Both of the these Menorahs underscore the spirit of Hanukkah and remind us that light will prevail even in the darkest of times. We are honored to light the Menorah for the last time at the White House alongside both the Wiesel and Peres families.</p>

<p class="default">
	<strong>Watch the President&#039;s remarks at the evening Hanukkah reception:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/b892J005r_I?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	From all of us at the White House, Chag Orim Sameach and Happy Hanukkah!</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 11:46:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/chanan-weissman-0&quot;&gt;Chanan Weissman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-314956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Brother&amp;#039;s Keeper: A Day of Action</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/14/my-brothers-keeper-day-action</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<span style="color:rgb(67, 67, 67); font-family:arial,helvetica,nimbus sans l,sans-serif; letter-spacing:0.13px">The White House is hosting its final MBK National Summit today, and launching our #IamMBK Digital Day of Action. As we near the end of the Obama administration, we are celebrating the historic progress underway to expand opportunity for all of our kids, and want to make sure that there is no doubt that MBK is here to stay! Tune in to the President&#039;s remarks today&nbsp;at 4:45pm ET.</span></p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cBG-kOLZsms?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	President Obama will deliver remarks at the Summit to lift up what’s working and applaud efforts to scale and sustain this critical work for the long-term. Here’s how you can get involved and take action right now.</p>

<p>
	<strong>#IamMBK Digital Day of Action:</strong></p>

<p>
	Today, Wednesday, December 14, we are launching a #IamMBK Day of Action to encourage more Americans to become mentors and do their part to help all kids achieve their dreams.</p>

<p>
	<strong><a href="https://www.serve.gov/mentor/mbk-day-action" target="_blank">Visit the Digital Day of Action website for more details, including sample tweets, shareable graphics, and videos you can post. Here’s a quick summary of how you can post, share, and tweet your support of this critical work.</a></strong></p>

<p>
	<strong>1. Post your support:</strong>&nbsp;Share with your followers the reasons that you support My Brother’s Keeper using the hashtag #IamMBK on Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram.</p>

<p>
	<strong>2. Share an infographic:</strong>&nbsp;Lift up the #IamMBK Digital Day of Action and help ignite the conversation by posting an infographic and driving your followers to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.serve.gov/mentor" target="_blank">mentor.gov</a>&nbsp;to get involved.</p>

<p>
	<strong>3. Share a mentoring image:</strong>&nbsp;Post of an image of a child you’ve mentored or of an individual that has mentored you. Tell your audience a little about that person in your post and direct them to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.serve.gov/mentor" target="_blank">mentor.gov</a>&nbsp;to sign up to become a mentor. Don’t forget to include #IamMBK!</p>

<p>
	<strong>4. Share a video:</strong>&nbsp;Record a video/snap telling your followers about the importance of mentorship and encouraging them to get involved in their local MBK community; direct them to mentor.gov to learn more. Don’t forget to include #IamMBK!</p>

<p>
	<strong>MBK National Summit Livestream:</strong></p>

<p>
	Watch President Obama’s remarks at 4:45pm ET, and be sure to check out the dynamic speakers at the forefront of the MBK movement. Access the livestream from 12:30pm ET to 6:30pm ET at <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/live">WH.gov/live</a>. See more information below on the sessions and speakers you won’t want to miss.</p>

<p>
	The MBK Summit is being co-hosted by the White House, the U.S. Department of Education, the MBK Alliance, Bloomberg Associates, and the Executives’ Alliance for Boys and Men of Color. See the line-up of speakers and sessions below.</p>

<p>
	<strong>12:30 PM: Opening &amp; Welcome Remarks</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Valerie Jarrett, Senior Advisor to the President</li>
	<li>
		Michael Smith, Special Assistant to the President and Director of My Brother’s Keeper</li>
	<li>
		Rafael López, Commissioner of the Administration on Children, Youth and Families (ACYF), Department of Health and Human Services</li>
</ul>

<p>
	<strong>1 PM: Panel: MBK: Youth Voices</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Frank Cobbs IV, Participant in MBK-Fulton County, GA and student at St. Johns College, NYC</li>
	<li>
		Devin Edwards, Participant in MBK-Boston and student at Bunker Hill Community College, Boston MA</li>
	<li>
		Luis Ramirez, Participant in MBKA Oakland Career and Opportunity Fair</li>
	<li>
		Jamal Jones, Baltimore Algebra Project</li>
</ul>

<p>
	<strong>1:40 PM: Panel: Shaping Policy, Transforming Lives</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Wade Henderson, President and CEO of the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights</li>
	<li>
		Broderick Johnson, Assistant to the President and Chair of the My Brother’s Keeper Task Force</li>
	<li>
		Tom Perez, Secretary of the Department of Labor</li>
	<li>
		John King, Secretary of the Department of Education</li>
	<li>
		Rashad Robinson, Executive Director, Color of Change</li>
</ul>

<p>
	<strong>2:20 PM: Panel: MBK Communities: Infrastructure and Impact</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Linda Gibbs, Principal, Bloomberg Associates</li>
	<li>
		Mayor Martin J. Walsh, Boston, MA</li>
	<li>
		Mayor Betsy Hodges, Minneapolis, MN</li>
	<li>
		Assemblyman Michael Blake, Bronx, NY</li>
	<li>
		Sarah Eagle Heart (Oglala Lakota), CEO, Native Americans in Philanthropy</li>
	<li>
		Malachi Hernandez, Participant in MBK-Boston</li>
</ul>

<p>
	<strong>3 PM: Panel: The Power of a Mentor; Igniting a Movement</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>
		David Dietz, Specialist, Social Responsibility, The National Basketball Association</li>
	<li>
		Bob Lanier, NBA Hall of Famer</li>
	<li>
		Dr. William R. Hite, Superintendent of The School District of Philadelphia, Success Mentor</li>
	<li>
		Jerron Hawkins, White House Mentee and student at Howard University, Washington, DC</li>
</ul>

<p>
	<strong>3:40 PM: Fireside Chat with Former Mayor Michael Nutter, Philadelphia, PA and Quamiir Trice, Participant in MBK-Philadelphia and student at Howard University, Washington, DC</strong></p>

<p>
	<strong>4:10 PM: Implicit Bias Training led by Bryant Marks, Ph.D, Commissioner, White House Initiative on Educational Excellence for African Americans</strong></p>

<p>
	<strong>4:45 PM: Remarks by the President</strong></p>

<p>
	<strong>5:10 PM: Panel: All Hands on Deck: Cross-Sector Solutions for Change</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Blair Taylor, CEO, My Brother’s Keeper Alliance</li>
	<li>
		Tonya Allen, President and CEO, Skillman Foundation</li>
	<li>
		Christopher Oechsli, President and CEO, The Atlantic Philanthropies</li>
	<li>
		Tony West, Executive Vice President, Government Affairs, General Counsel and Corporate Secretary, PepsiCo</li>
	<li>
		Lashon Amado, Opportunity Youth United</li>
</ul>

<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 09:59:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/broderick-johnson&quot;&gt;Broderick Johnson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-314396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investing in a Safer, Strong Baltimore: A Model for the President&amp;#039;s Approach to Working with Cities</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/14/investing-safer-strong-baltimore-model-presidents-approach-working-cities</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	In the spring of 2015, the White House established a special Taskforce for Baltimore City. The Taskforce was charged with marshalling Federal funds, programs, and expertise to address some of the city’s social and economic challenges, like violent crime, high levels of unemployment and limited economic opportunity in low-income neighborhoods.</p>

<p>
	Baltimore is home to dedicated and creative public servants inside and out of government, many of whom are national leaders and experts in their field. Working with these leaders and with Maryland’s Congressional Delegation, the Taskforce focused on jobs, public health and safety. The Taskforce also prioritized investing in the long-term prosperity of the city through transportation, infrastructure, and the environment.</p>

<p>
	Today, the White House is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/White%20House%20Taskforce%20for%20Baltimore%20City.pdf">releasing a new report</a>&nbsp;that highlights the progress of the Taskforce and its accomplishments over the past eighteen months.</p>

<p>
	For example, to help address Baltimore’s unemployment rate, the Taskforce focused on creating new workforce programs, providing new opportunities for young people, and supporting small businesses. The Department of Labor funded One Baltimore for Jobs, a new initiative out of the Mayor’s Office that has helped hundreds of Baltimoreans land new jobs. In collaboration with the Taskforce and many public and private sector partners, Baltimore City also successfully grew the city’s youth summer jobs program by 60%, creating new professional opportunities for 6,000 young people over the course of two summers.</p>

<p>
	To address public safety and public health, the Taskforce focused on protecting young people in and out of school, funding programs to make streets and neighborhoods safer, and reforming the Baltimore Police Department. For example, the U.S. Department of Justice and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services identified $1 million in funding over two years to keep Baltimore City Health Department’s Safe Streets program alive. With this funding, the Baltimore City Health Department was able to sustain and expand current violence prevention efforts in Park Heights, Sandtown Winchester, Cherry Hill and East Baltimore, and significantly reduce gun violence among youth ages 14 to 24.</p>

<p>
	To lay the foundations for future prosperity, the Taskforce focused on investing in transportation, establishing new anchor institutions and commercial hubs, improving Baltimore’s parks and green spaces, increasing food access, and building civic capacity. For example, the Department of Transportation supported Baltimore City and the State of Maryland with two $10 million TIGER transportation grants for the Port of Baltimore and for improvements to North Avenue, respectively.</p>

<p>
	In many cases, from public health to workforce programs, the initiatives up and running in Baltimore are becoming national models, reflecting the commitment and caliber of the city’s citizens and leaders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	The Administration’s work in Baltimore reflects a broader push by President Obama to change how the Federal government works with cities, towns, and other communities. The President’s “community solutions” approach emphasizes closer coordination, data-based decision-making, and rigorous evaluation.</p>

<p>
	Citizens and local leaders in communities like Baltimore need a Federal Government that is more effective, responsive, and collaborative in addressing their needs and challenges. Far too often, the Federal Government has taken a “one-size-fits-all” approach to working with communities and left local leaders on their own to navigate Federal resources and programs.</p>

<p>
	Responding to the call for change from local officials and leaders nationwide, and grounded in the belief that the best solutions come from the bottom up, not from the top down, under the Obama Administration, Federal agencies have increasingly taken on a different approach to working with communities to deliver better outcomes in more than 1,800 cities, towns, regions, and tribal communities nationwide. The Federal-local partnership in the City of Baltimore exemplifies the Administration’s “Community Solutions” approach, which calls for an integrated Federal government to align resources and cultivate working relationships with local stakeholders to respond to the needs of the community.</p>

<p>
	Because of the groundwork that the Obama Administration has laid, the Federal government will continue to take a “community solutions” approach in its work in Baltimore and other cities, ensuring that the progress that the Taskforce has made in Baltimore is only the foundation for future Federal investments and partnerships.</p>

<p>
	<em>Nate Loewentheil, Special Assistant to President for Economic Policy&nbsp;</em></p>

<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/broderick-johnson&quot;&gt;Broderick Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, Nate Loewentheil</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-314326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Letters That Explain Why President Obama Is Signing the Cures Act</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/12/3-letters-explain-why-president-obama-signing-cures-act</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aOraimWg5bs?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p class="rtecenter"><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-blue" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/13/god-willing-bill-will-save-lives" target="_self">Read the Vice President&#039;s Message</a></span></span>&nbsp;<span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-blue" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ibessmTZ5Dc&amp;t=177s" target="_self">Watch the President&#039;s Remarks</a></span></span></p>

<hr />
<p>Today, President Obama signed&nbsp;into law the 21st Century Cures Act, bipartisan legislation that will go a long way toward bringing about the medical breakthroughs we need to meet some of the biggest health challenges facing Americans today. No matter what corner of the country you live in, you or someone in your life has been touched by cancer, the opioid epidemic, devastating&nbsp;illnesses or serious mental health issues. The Cures Act makes significant investments in innovative technologies and research that could find a cure for Alzheimer&#039;s, end cancer as we know it, and help those who are seeking treatment for opioid addiction.&nbsp;</p>

<p><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><img alt="Cures Act investments" data-widget="image" height="450" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/cures_5ways.jpg" width="900" /></span></p>

<p><strong>Read these three letters to learn why President Obama is so committed to investing in the future of health in America.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<h4 class="semibold">Eugene Ammon, Jr.,&nbsp;Columbus, OH</h4>

<p><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><img alt="Letter from Eugene Ammon" data-widget="image" height="726" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Ammonletter.PNG" width="880" /></span></p>

<p>Transcript:&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Hello Mr. President, my name is Eugene Ammon. I am from Columbus Ohio. I am sending this message in regards to the growing concern in this country about addiction especially the growing number of people who die each year because of this. I personally lost my mother 18 months ago to a heroin overdose and will most likely be attending my sisters funeral, a mother of 3, by the years end as she is also an addict and has been diagnosed with heart problems and Hep C. Both i assume due to her addiction and her life style that has led her to being arrested for soliciting more times than i&nbsp;can count.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">My concern is that this has opened my eyes as to how only those with an abundance of resources have steady and consistent access to the treatment necessary to actually treat themselves. My sister was recently released out into the world, again, without anywhere to go as waiting lists for facilities combined with over crowding in the jail system meant she would be put in a position no one could possibly succeed in.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">There are facilities available but they need you to be insured. To be blunt but even with the expanded access to health insurance this is not something a prostitute with a heroin problem is walking around with.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Let me be clear that her decisions are hers and hers alone. They were my mothers decisions. However I cant help but wonder what kind of difference it would make if one could have access to this kind of help the moment they wanted it. I feel there are enough resources to make this a reality, I also think this would be cheaper over the long run than the countless unpaid ER visits that are occurring everyday from things like overdoses and infections.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Its too late for my family. Its too late for me. Its not too late for countless others.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">I don&#039;t know what they policy answers are. I as an average american can only reach out to those who might with what i see as a problem and hope someone notices or cares. I do know this is health crisis not just a criminal one and i hope for a policy approach sooner rather than later that will deal with this as such.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">If you or anyone happens to read this i thank you for your time.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>More Americans now die every year from drug overdoses than&nbsp;in motor vehicle crashes, and the majority involve opioids. The Cures Act invests $1 billion dollars to combat the heroin and prescription&nbsp;opioid epidemic, as the President’s called for in his budget. The Administration is committed to ensuring that these funds are disbursed quickly and effectively starting in early 2017.</strong></p>

<p><strong><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-blue" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/08/continued-rise-opioid-overdose-deaths-2015-shows-urgent-need-treatment" target="_self">The Opioid Epidemic</a></span></span></strong></p>

<h4 class="semibold">KathRYn Green, Santa Monica, California</h4>

<p><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><img alt="Letter from Kathryn Green" data-widget="image" height="540" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/kathryngreenletter.PNG" width="880" /></span></p>

<p>Transcript:&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Dear President Obama and Vice President Biden,</p>

<p class="rteindent1">My name is Kathryn Green and I&#039;m a mother of a 14 month old daughter, a high school teacher in Los Angeles, and a wife of a husband who is battling brain cancer. While this is the first time I&#039;m writing to offer my deepest condolences for the loss of the Vice President&#039;s son, his family was in my prayers upon hearing the news, and will continue to be. I read in the news this morning that the Vice President was visiting the Fred Hutchinson Research Center on Monday, and I wanted to thank him for continuing to bring this terrible disease into the spotlight, and thank you both for being that ever-hopeful light in finding a way to manage cancer with your Moonshot initiative. I sat with my daughter on my lap and listened to the State of the Union address, and at one years old, I was delighted that she clapped along as the audience applauded. There are so many problems and issues that need healing in this country, and I&#039;m deeply grateful that both President Obama and Vice President Biden are standing with the patients, families, and communities who have been touched by this disease. I will continue to follow your administrations lead and support you in your endeavors, however they manifest over the next few months and years. It is with the most sincerity and humbleness that I ask for your office to continue supporting the institutes, scientists, and research centers, who will, no doubt. be the harbinger of a bright future in a diagnosis which sees only dark clouds ahead. Thank you again for all of the work you have done, and will continue to do. I will be cheering from the sidelines, and envisioning better days to come.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Warmly,</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Kathryn Green</p>

<p><strong>In his last State of the Union address, President Obama asked Vice President Joe Biden to be at the head of "mission control" in a new moonshot effort to end cancer as we know it. The Cancer Moonshot&#039;s ultimate goal is to&nbsp;make a decade’s worth of advances in cancer prevention, diagnosis, and treatment, in five years. The Cures Act invests $1.8 billion in this initiative -- important funding that will&nbsp;support investment in promising new therapies like cancer immunotherapy, new prevention tools, cancer vaccine development, novel early detection tools, and pediatric cancer interventions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-blue" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cancermoonshot" target="_self">The Cancer Moonshot </a></span></span></p>

<h4 class="semibold">Michelle McRee, Atwater, California&nbsp;</h4>

<p><em>Michelle McRee first wrote the President in December of 2015 in frustration over her 15-year-old granddaughter&#039;s inability to receive the mental health services she needed. She questioned whether the health care law and the U.S. health care system would ever be able to address her daughters needs: "I am sick and I am disgusted with knowing that in a few weeks my grandchild will be coming home with another &#039;band-aid&#039; to treat her disorders," she wrote. "I live in fear of the day that my daughter will tell me that my grandchild has taken her own life, due to a mental health disorder that she can receive only minimal treatment for."&nbsp;</em></p>

<p><em>The President responded to let her know he was listening and directed his team to help advise her on the best way to find support. This is her letter in response:&nbsp;</em></p>

<p><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><img alt="Letter from Michelle McRee" data-widget="image" height="753" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/McReeletter.PNG" width="880" /></span></p>

<p>Transcript:&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Dear Mr. President,&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">I wanted to take a moment to thank you for listening. Your administration&#039;s response and assistance, at your behalf, has shown us how agencies can work together to help families such as ours. When I first wrote to you last fall, about my grandchild&#039;s situation and our frustrations in getting the recommended care for her, I did so not just out of frustration but out of bitter anger as well. Since then I have learned a lot. I learned that the resources were already there and had been for quite some time. While it is true that finding these resources is more difficult than it should be, it is up to us parents and guardians to be proactive for our children from the very beginning, not after the fifth hospitalization and out of bitter frustration.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">I blamed you and I blamed your healthcare policy for our struggles and i have since learned that wasn&#039;t fair. While I am not a member of your political party (no, I didn&#039;t vote for you) and have often been critical of this new healthcare policy, I am forever grateful to you sir, for taking the time to listen, to help, and to make my grandchild&#039;s day when she read your letter.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Since becoming my grandchild&#039;s caregiver, and during being the primary caregiver for my parents before their deaths these past couple years, I have lost a lot. I have had to make the choice to give up a job (twice now), I am losing my car due to being financially unable to afford it, and we may have to move soon. Unfortunately. those choices have to be made because our system, both state and federal, does have many gaps. But they were choices that I made fully aware and the only thing that i have lost are just that ... "things", and can be replaced. I cannot replace the time I had with my parents, nor the joy in seeing my grandchild progress daily in learning to cope in healthy ways with her disorders whil still remaining here at home. I cannot replace the gratitude of having one of the best mental health support teams that I have ever had the honor of knowing. And I cannot replace the humbling realization that we can, and are often, wrong in where we place blame. That my government didn&#039;t fail my grandchild. My goverment stepped in and provided the professional support for us to help my grandchild.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Again, I thank you President Obama for what you have done for my family. I wish you and your family many happy years.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Sincerely,</p>

<p class="rteindent1">Michelle R. McRee&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>The Cures Act includes bipartisan mental health provisions, including improved coordination between primary care and behavioral health services, reauthorization of important programs focused on suicide prevention and other prevention services, and mental health and substance use disorder parity provisions that build on the work of the President&#039;s Mental Health and Substance Use Disorder Parity Task Force.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-blue" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/10/27/our-report-president-mental-health-and-substance-use-disorder-parity" target="_self">Mental Health &amp; Substance Abuse Report</a></span></span></p>

<p><strong>The Cures Act also makes a significant investment of nearly $3 billion to continue the President&#039;s signature biomedical research initiatives -- the BRAIN and Precision Medicine Initiatives --&nbsp;over the next decade to tackle diseases like Alzheimer&#039;s and create new research models to find cures and better target treatments.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://letterstopresidentobama.tumblr.com/post/140003534334/your-blood-type-is-specific-to-your-body-matching">Read what that Precision Medicine Initiative has meant in another letter writer&#039;s life here</a>. Then dig deeper into the medical possibilities and hope that&nbsp;these initiatives -- and support from the Cures Act -- can deliver in the near future.&nbsp;</p>

<p><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-blue" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/precision-medicine" target="_self">Precision Medicine Initiative</a></span></span>&nbsp;<span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-blue" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/share/brain-initiative" target="_self">BRAIN Initiative</a></span></span></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 20:01:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/tanya-somanader&quot;&gt;Tanya Somanader&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-314176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vice President Biden: God Willing, This Bill Will Save Lives</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/13/god-willing-bill-will-save-lives</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<em>Vice President Joe Biden sent the following message to the White House email list ahead of joining President Obama later today as he signs the Cures Act into law. You can tune in <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/12/3-letters-explain-why-president-obama-signing-cures-act">here</a> at 2:00PM ET:</em>&nbsp;</p>

<hr />
<p>
	Last Monday night, forty-four years after the people of Delaware first sent me to the United States Senate, I presided over a Senate vote for one of the last times.</p>

<p>
	As Vice President of the United States and president of the Senate, I served as the presiding officer as the Senate moved forward on the 21st Century Cures Act, a bill that will harness America’s best minds in science, medicine, and technology to tackle the biggest health challenges of our time.</p>

<p>
	This bill will help us combat the heroin and prescription opioid epidemic ripping apart families and communities. It invests in programs to improve mental health treatment and suicide prevention. It will provide resources for President Obama’s BRAIN and Precision Medicine initiatives, so that our world-class researchers can figure out how to better prevent, treat, and eventually cure Alzheimer&#039;s, epilepsy, and traumatic brain injuries.</p>

<p>
	And this is the part that&#039;s personal for me and for millions of Americans: The 21st Century Cures Act invests $1.8 billion to help us end cancer as we know it. For over a year, I&#039;ve been leading our National Cancer Moonshot to fundamentally change the culture of our fight against cancer and inject a sense of urgency into it. This bill goes a long way to help us -- investing in promising new therapies, enhancing prevention and detection efforts in every community regardless of zip code, and bringing us closer to the day when there are vaccines for all kinds of cancer, just as we have them for measles or mumps.</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/12/3-letters-explain-why-president-obama-signing-cures-act?utm_source=email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=email659-text1&amp;utm_campaign=cures" target="_blank">God willing, this bill will save lives.</a></p>

<p>
	While I was presiding in the Senate, my colleagues from both sides of the aisle renamed the section of this bill on cancer research for my son, Beau, who lost his battle with brain cancer, but like countless Americans who lost their own battles, inspires us to do everything we can for the loved ones we can save. My thanks goes out to the bipartisan leadership -- Democrats and Republicans in the House and the Senate -- who ensured that this important bill became law. Without this true bipartisan support, this piece of legislation, which will help millions of Americans, would not have been possible.</p>

<p>
	Today, President Obama will sign the 21st Century Cures Act into law. One last time in our Administration, I will stand right by him at a signing ceremony -- proud of our country, and proud of the work we’ve done to give people hope.</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/12/3-letters-explain-why-president-obama-signing-cures-act?utm_source=email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=email659-text2&amp;utm_campaign=cures" target="_blank">I hope you&#039;ll join me.</a></p>

<p>
	Thanks,</p>

<p>
	Joe</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 11:27:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/ken-meyer&quot;&gt;Ken Meyer&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-314256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Address: It’s Time to Get Covered on the Health Insurance Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/10/weekly-address-its-time-get-covered-health-insurance-marketplace</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	In this week’s address, President Obama discussed Open Enrollment on the Health Insurance Marketplace, which began November 1. The deadline to sign up for coverage beginning on January 1 is this Thursday, December 15, and the final deadline to sign up for 2017 coverage is January 31. Today, thanks to the Affordable Care Act, every American with insurance is covered by the strongest set of consumer protections in history. For every person with insurance, preventive care is available with no cost sharing; there are no more annual or lifetime limits on essential health care; you can’t get charged more just for being a woman; young people can stay on a parent’s plan until they turn 26; seniors get discounts on their prescriptions; and no one can be denied coverage because of a pre-existing condition. Although Republicans in Congress want to repeal this law, the President emphasized that we should build on the progress we’ve already made.</p>

<p>
	<strong>To sign up for health care coverage, visit <a href="http://HealthCare.gov">HealthCare.gov</a> or call 1-800-318-2596.&nbsp;</strong><br />
	&nbsp;<br />
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1CW6NbZvR_w?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/10/weekly-address-its-time-get-covered-health-insurance-marketplace">Transcript</a> | <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/videos/2016/December/20161210_Weekly_Address_HD.mp4">MP4</a> | <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/videos/2016/December/20161210_Weekly_Address.mp3">MP3</a></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/melanie-garunay&quot;&gt;Melanie Garunay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-313641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Gamers Get Health Care Coverage (An Epic Win)</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/08/helping-gamers-get-health-care-coverage-epic-win</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-tsVyHAkTN0?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	You heard it from Shaq himself: on Monday, December 12, the White House will host a competitive gaming event to help people sign up for health care coverage at <a href="https://www.healthcare.gov/">HealthCare.gov</a>. Tune in to <a href="http://twitch.tv/GetCovered">twitch.tv/GetCovered</a>&nbsp;at 4 PM&nbsp;Eastern to join in!</p>

<p>
	Millions of Americans participate in eSports (that’s Electronic Sports, or competitive video games) to connect with friends, to challenge themselves, to root for their favorite eSports team, and to be part of a rapidly growing community. In fact, more people now watch major eSports competitions than the number of people who watch the NBA finals or World Series.</p>

<p>
	As eSports grow in popularity and become increasingly mainstream, gamers are increasing in numbers and diversity. About 77 percent of men between ages 18-29 say that they play games, and so do 57 percent of women in the same age group.</p>

<p>
	Thanks to the Affordable Care Act, 20 million Americans now know the peace of mind and financial security of having health insurance. Young adults had the highest uninsured rates before the Affordable Care Act and have seen the sharpest drop in uninsured rates since 2010. But millions of millennials remain uninsured, and many of those uninsured young adults could qualify for tax credits on the Health Insurance Marketplace to keep insurance affordable. In fact, most HealthCare.gov consumers can find a plan for under $75 a month, less than their cell phone bill.</p>

<p>
	Gamers, like everyone, deserve high-quality health care coverage. Engaging the expanding gamer community is part of the Administration’s effort to meet people where they are to help them find a health care plan that’s best for them. That’s why <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/02/11/esports-athletes-want-you-get-covered">last year</a>, many from the eSports industry, including ESL, Twitch.tv and GEER, helped launch an initiative to encourage more gamers to sign up for health care at HealthCare.gov. And this year, HHS has forged <a href="https://www.cms.gov/Newsroom/MediaReleaseDatabase/Press-releases/2016-Press-releases-items/2016-09-27.html">innovative partnerships</a> with digital platforms to help young adults understand that quality, affordable health care is within reach.</p>

<p>
	I know the power of video games first hand, and how incredible the gaming community can be. In high school, I had severe health challenges that led to hospitalization (and fortunately my care was covered as a dependent under my parent’s plan). During my recovery after the hospital, I helped lead a guild in the popular multiplayer online game World of Warcraft. Playing the game was empowering; it gave me a community where I could be myself, and I met players who became lasting friends, like Aceris the Druid, who’s also a librarian in Boston, or Chyra the Healer, who’s also a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/nation-of-makers">Maker </a>in Michigan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	And we also absolutely rekt (humiliatingly defeated) our opponents in PvP (Player versus Player). The competitions brought us together, helped make our group a family, and made us part of a community. We looked out for each other. Gamers have other gamers’ backs FTW (For the Win).</p>

<p>
	So join us and members of the gaming community for a live-streamed event at <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/GetCovered">twitch.tv/GetCovered</a> on Monday, December 12, and help your fellow gamers #GetCovered at HealthCare.gov.</p>

<p>
	<em>Erik Martin is a Policy Advisor for the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy.&nbsp;</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Erik Martin</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-312686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 100 Companies Sign the Equal Pay Pledge</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/07/over-100-companies-sign-equal-pay-pledge</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="President Barack Obama signs executive actions to strengthen enforcement of equal pay laws for women, at an event marking Equal Pay Day in the East Room of the White House, April 8, 2014. The President signs the Presidential Memorandum -- Advancing Pay Equality Through Compensation Data Collection, and an Executive Order regarding Non-Retaliation for Disclosure of Compensation Information. Lilly Ledbetter stands to the left of the signing table. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)" height="683" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/14332155695_53bc4c69d1_b%20%281%29.jpg" width="1024" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 1024px;">
		President Barack Obama signs executive actions to strengthen enforcement of equal pay laws for women, at an event marking Equal Pay Day in the East Room of the White House, April 8, 2014. The President signs the Presidential Memorandum -- Advancing Pay Equality Through Compensation Data Collection, and an Executive Order regarding Non-Retaliation for Disclosure of Compensation Information. Lilly Ledbetter stands to the left of the signing table. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	Growing up, I never once thought that my gender could influence my perceived worth. I was lucky that my mother and father set a standard for me that as long as I worked hard and earned it, I could do anything or be anyone that I wanted, and expect to be treated the same as everybody else.</p>

<p>
	My mother was an amazing public school teacher, and while the hours were often long and intense, she never questioned whether her work was valued the same as her male counterparts. To a fault, I continued to believe that policies and practices like this were a given, never once wondering if it would be any different in any other sector.</p>

<p>
	The truth is that fair pay policies are not the norm. Many people are unaware that women and men are not equally paid for equal work. That is, until people start talking about it.</p>

<p>
	As Director of the White House Business Council, it has been an honor to work for a President and Administration that places such high importance on women’s equality and opportunity. The President signed into law <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/remarks-president-barack-obama-lilly-ledbetter-fair-pay-restoration-act-bill-signin">Lilly Ledbetter Fair Pay Act</a> as his first piece of legislation, and the work to support America’s working families has continued from there. He created a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/rss_viewer/equal_pay_task_force.pdf">National Equal Pay Task Force</a>, signed a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2013/05/10/presidential-memorandum-advancing-pay-equality-federal-government-and-le">Presidential Memorandum</a> directing the Office of Personnel Management to develop a government-wide strategy to address the gender pay gap in the federal workforce, and issued an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2014/04/08/executive-order-non-retaliation-disclosure-compensation-information">Executive Order</a> to protect employees from being discriminated against for wanting to inquire or discuss their compensation.</p>

<p>
	And as part of the <a href="http://www.theunitedstateofwomen.org/">United State of Women Summit</a> in June, the White House issued a call to action to America’s businesses, both large and small, to pledge to be open and transparent about their pay-bands and to address unconscious bias and structural barriers.</p>

<p>
	<strong>Today, we’re announcing</strong> <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/07/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-new-commitments-equal-pay-pledge"><strong>44 new employers</strong></a> <strong>who have signed on to the Equal Pay Pledge, bringing the total number to over 100 businesses who have embraced equal pay policies and who understand that doing good is also good for business.</strong></p>

<p>
	<img alt="Equal Pay Pledge" height="400" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/equalPayPledge_120716.jpg" width="800" /></p>

<p>
	Women make up nearly half of the U.S. labor force and more women than ever are the breadwinners in their families. Companies like SoulCycle, whose studio leadership positions are 86 percent held by women, understand that empowering women leads to a thriving culture and business.&nbsp;<br />
	And if companies already implement these types of policies, they understand that those policies are just the beginning, not the end. Companies like Adobe have already published their pay data but will continue their commitment to these measures. Companies like Autodesk know that reviewing their data regularly is important, but so is the constant self-reflection to make sure they are living up to their own standards.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	I am proud to stand with the over 100 businesses who are taking on a critical role to reduce the national gender pay gap and create a world where our daughters have the same chance to pursue their dreams as our sons.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/07/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-new-commitments-equal-pay-pledge">Learn more</a> about the Equal&nbsp;</em><em>Pay Pledge, and see the full list of companies that have signed on.</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 13:52:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/diana-doukas&quot;&gt;Diana Doukas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-312236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FDA Takes Action to Deliver Lower-Cost, Innovative Hearing Aids to Millions More Americans</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/07/fda-takes-action-deliver-lower-cost-innovative-hearing-aids-millions-more-americans</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<a href="http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm532005.htm"><strong>Today, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is launching a process to facilitate the availability of over-the-counter hearing aids—an announcement with the potential to positively impact millions of Americans.</strong></a></p>

<p>
	Tens of millions of Americans currently suffer from hearing loss, often age-related, but many either don’t realize they’ve been affected or cannot afford basic hearing aids—which currently cost an average of $2,300 apiece. (That means, for a pair, most consumers are forced to plunk down a hefty sum of more than $4,600.)</p>

<p>
	Today, consumers can buy simple corrective lenses—reading glasses—over the counter, but the same is not true for hearing aids. And while hearing aids do not restore perfect hearing, allowing over-the-counter sale would facilitate the availability of more innovative, lower-cost products, enabling millions of people who are negatively impacted by hearing loss to better their daily lives.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="semibold">
	<strong>Why this matters, by the numbers:</strong></h2>

<h2 class="formal rtecenter">
	<strong>30 million</strong></h2>

<p class="rtecenter">
	30 million Americans currently suffer from&nbsp;hearing loss, which is often age-related.</p>

<h2 class="formal rtecenter">
	<strong>&gt;$2,300</strong></h2>

<p class="rtecenter">
	Hearing aids currently cost an average of more than $2,300 apiece (i.e. for both ears, they cost an average of more than $4,600.) Over-the-counter products offer the prospect of bringing these costs down into the hundreds—instead of thousands—of dollars.</p>

<h2 class="formal rtecenter">
	<strong>&lt; 1/5</strong></h2>

<p class="rtecenter">
	Due to the high cost and the overly burdensome steps needed to access hearing aids, fewer than one in five Americans who could benefit from technology to help them hear better actually get the assistance of a hearing aid. Many of these consumers who don’t suffer from severe hearing loss just need help hearing a little better in a loud restaurant, for example.</p>

<h2 class="formal rtecenter">
	<strong>10,000</strong></h2>

<p class="rtecenter">
	Roughly 10,000 Americans are turning 65 every single day. Over 25 percent of Americans aged 60-69 have hearing loss, and that rises to over 50 percent for 70-79 years of age and over 75 percent for Americans aged 80+ years. The ongoing retirement of the baby boomers and increased longevity mean that the number of Americans who could benefit from an over-the-counter hearing aid will only be growing. That’s why AARP and the Hearing Loss Association of America (HLAA) have both supported allowing an over-the-counter product.</p>

<h2 class="formal rtecenter">
	<strong>6</strong></h2>

<p class="rtecenter">
	Currently only six manufacturers produce nearly all hearing aids, and only one of those companies is based in the United States. Opening up the hearing aid market to innovative, lower-cost, over-the-counter options brings with it the prospect of expanding the number of options for consumers and creating opportunities for economic growth and job creation in the United States. That’s why consumer electronics stakeholders representing innovative American companies have supported expanding the options and technologies available.</p>

<h2 class="semibold">
	<strong>So, what happens next? </strong></h2>

<p>
	As a first step toward breaking down barriers, FDA has announced that it does not intend to enforce the requirement for American adults to get a medical evaluation before obtaining most hearing aids. The vast majority of people waive this requirement already. Currently, audiological services are bundled into the overall price of a hearing aid—and the market is constrained by bulk purchasing arrangements between hearing aid dispensers and the major manufacturers. Allowing the sale of over-the-counter hearing aids has the potential to deliver tens of millions of Americans the prospect of better hearing at much lower cost by increasing competition and innovation in the hearing aid market.</p>

<p>
	In 2015, the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology (PCAST) <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/10/26/%E2%80%8Bpcast-recommends-changes-promote-innovation-hearing-technologies">examined the technology, regulation, and marketplace of hearing aids</a>, leading them to recommend that FDA approve an over-the-counter device.&nbsp; Now—after a <a href="http://nationalacademies.org/hmd/reports/2016/Hearing-Health-Care-for-Adults.aspx">two-year study</a> by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine that also called for an over-the-counter product in alignment with the PCAST recommendation—FDA is announcing it’s ready to take the necessary steps to move forward. Today’s actions are yet another in a series in response to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/04/15/executive-order-steps-increase-competition-and-better-inform-consumers">President Obama’s Executive Order promoting competition</a> to benefit consumers, workers, and small businesses.</p>

<h2 class="semibold">
	<strong>The Bottom Line</strong></h2>

<p>
	Today’s announcement could start a movement toward over-the-counter hearing aids that will cost a fraction of the $2,300 apiece of current products, helping more of the 30 million Americans who need assistance.</p>

<p>
	<em>Charlie Anderson is a Special Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</em>.&nbsp;<em>Ashley Predith is the Executive Director of PCAST.&nbsp;</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 09:41:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/charlie-anderson&quot;&gt;Charlie Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, Ashley Predith</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-312131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Live: President Obama Reviews His Approach to Counterterrorism </title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/06/watch-live-president-obama-reviews-his-approach-counterterrorism</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<hr />
<h2 class="semibold">
	Watch live at 4:10pm ET to hear President Obama speak on his Administration&#039;s approach to counterterrorism:&nbsp;</h2>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_lL0yFg5K7w?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<hr />
<p>
	President Obama is in Tampa, Florida today to personally thank some of the men and women who have been at the forefront of the global fight against terrorism. While at MacDill Air Force Base, he will also deliver his last major speech dedicated to his national security record in which he will summarize what we&#039;ve accomplished at home and abroad over the last eight years; how we&#039;ve approached the threat of terrorism; ;and how he he believes the nation can pursue a successful and sustainable counterterrorism policy in the years to come.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	From the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, to the emergence of ISIL, to the importance of diplomacy and global development, President Obama will review exactly what he did as Commander-in-Chief and the lessons that can be drawn from this approach. Make sure you watch at 4:10pm ET.&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 13:01:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/tanya-somanader&quot;&gt;Tanya Somanader&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Year of Action Supporting Computer Science for All</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/05/year-action-supporting-computer-science-all</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="CS_correct" height="600" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/csForAll_120516_correct.jpg" width="1200" /></p>

<p>
	In President Obama’s final State of the Union Address, he issued a bold call to action to give every child the opportunity to learn computer science. He did so because computing is becoming increasingly relevant to America’s economy, cybersecurity, and national security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2014/12/10/president-obama-first-president-write-line-code">He also thinks it’s a lot of fun!</a></p>

<p>
	Since then, 2016 has been a <strong>year of action</strong> in support of computer science, <strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/05/fact-sheet-year-action-supporting-computer-science-all">with new announcements made today</a></strong>. This year alone, 14 new states have expanded CS education, more than <strong>500 organizations</strong> have responded to the President’s call to action, and a new AP-CS course launched this fall that is already being offered in more than 2,000 classrooms. In addition, 15 federal agencies are coordinating efforts to expand CS education, with new investments and guidance.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/05/fact-sheet-year-action-supporting-computer-science-all">Learn more about all of today&#039;s announcements</a>.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>
	As a year of action 2016 builds on a decade of national, state, and grassroots activity to revitalize K-12 computer&nbsp;science education. A clear example of that steady growth and momentum has been <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/10/27/call-new-csforall-actions-during-computer-science-education-week">Computer Science Education Week</a> (CSEdWeek).</p>

<p>
	First launched in 2009 with a resolution in the U.S. House of Representatives, and timed in recognition of the birthday of computing pioneer and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/photos-and-video/video/2016/11/22/president-obama-awards-presidential-medal-freedom">Medal&nbsp;of&nbsp;Freedom</a>&nbsp;recipient&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2014/12/22/honoring-grace-hopper">Admiral Grace Murray Hopper</a>, CSEdWeek has since grown into a global event celebrated worldwide where millions of students, educators, parents, and industry volunteers participate in events and activities to inform and educate students about computer science and career opportunities in technology.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="image-center">
	<figure class="image-captioned">
		<img alt="CSA" height="485" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/CSA.png" width="657" />
		<figcaption style="max-width: 657px;">
			<em>Students and families learn coding together during Family Code Night at Riverside Unified School District organized in collaboration with the Inland Code Consortium, a new effort to bring computer science to nine school districts across the Inland Empire of California. Photo Credit: RUSD Communications</em></figcaption>
	</figure>
</div>

<p>
	In 2013, President Obama <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2013/12/09/don-t-just-play-your-phone-program-it">kicked off CSEdWeek</a> with a video message urging students to try their hands at computer science saying, “don’t just play on your phone, program it.”</p>

<p>
	During CSEdWeek 2014, President Obama became&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2014/12/10/president-obama-first-president-write-line-code" target="_blank">the first President to write computer code</a>&nbsp;as a part of a&nbsp;student coding activity&nbsp;at the White House, and last year the White House hosted the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/12/08/administration-kicks-participation-computer-science-education-week">CS Tech Jam</a> to bring developers, educators, and students together to develop new innovations for CS education.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yE6IfCrqg3s?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	This week, Obama administration officials, <span style="color:rgb(67, 67, 67); font-family:arial,helvetica,nimbus sans l,sans-serif; letter-spacing:0.13px; line-height:18.005px">alongside hundreds of local and national organizations,&nbsp;</span>are joining community-led CSEdWeek events across the nation, ranging from the Inland CSforAll Summit, which brings together school districts and community partners across central California, to the BotBall Junior tournament in Oklahoma City where 1,000 students will show off their software skills as they compete with autonomous robots, to the “Cuppa Code” meet-up for new CS teachers and tech professionals in Arlington, Virginia, hosted by CodeVA and Starbucks to the General Services Administration’s “Grace Hopper” Hackathon for open government.</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://csedweek.org/" target="_blank">Find an event in your community</a>, and join the movement to bring computer science to all of our children!</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 12:22:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/ruthe-farmer&quot;&gt;Ruthe Farmer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/kumar-garg&quot;&gt;Kumar Garg&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating International Day of Persons with Disabilities </title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/03/celebrating-international-day-persons-disabilities</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<blockquote class="blockquote-2">
	“The changes achieved in the last two decades speak to what people can accomplish when they refuse to accept the world as it is. Today let us once again reach for the world that should be -- one where all people, regardless of country or disability, enjoy equal access, equal opportunity, and the freedom to realize their limitless potential.”
	<div class="citation">
		President Obama, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2013/12/02/presidential-proclamation-international-day-persons-disabilities-2013">International Day of Persons With Disabilities, 2013</a></div>
</blockquote>

<div contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1">
	<figure class="image-captioned">
		<img alt="An interpreter signs in the foreground while President Barack Obama, with Vice President Joe Biden, delivers remarks during a reception for the 25th anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) in the East Room of the White House, July 20, 2015. " height="1494" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/president_obama_during_ada_1.jpg" width="2240" />
		<figcaption style="max-width: 2240px;">
			An interpreter signs in the foreground while President Barack Obama, with Vice President Joe Biden, delivers remarks during a recetion for the 25th anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) in the East Room of the White House, July 20, 2015. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)</figcaption>
	</figure>
</div>

<p>
	Today is the International Day of Persons with Disabilities -- a day to unify around ensuring a better, more equitable world. An annual celebration promoted by the United Nations since 1992, the day is dedicated to helping spread awareness and understanding of disability issues while championing the extraordinary achievements and contributions of persons with disabilities across the globe.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	This year’s International Day of Persons with Disabilities theme is dedicated to assessing the current status of <a href="http://www.ohchr.org/EN/HRBodies/CRPD/Pages/ConventionRightsPersonsWithDisabilities.aspx">Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities</a>&nbsp;(CRPD) and the <a href="https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/?menu=1300">United Nation’s Sustainable Development Goals</a>, which lay foundation to create a more inclusive and diverse future.</p>

<p>
	Currently, around&nbsp;1 billion people live with a disability, making up around 15&nbsp;percent of the world&#039;s total population. Since taking office, President Obama has been committed to nurturing a society that values the contributions of all citizens, at home and abroad -- from expanding educational and employment opportunities for people with disabilities, to enforcing the Americans with Disabilities Act, to increasing accessibility to innovation and technology, to signing the CRPD. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/issues/disabilities">Read more on our progress here.</a></p>

<p>
	While we have come a long way as a society since the first International Day of Persons with Disabilities 24 years ago -- but we still have more work to do in combating discrimination and removing the barriers that remain.</p>

<p>
	A lifelong advocate for disability rights, Judith Heumann is internationally recognized leader in the disability community and a lifelong civil rights advocate for disadvantaged people. Heumann currently serves as Special Advisor for International Disability Rights at the U.S. Department of State, a position that President Obama created and appointed her to in 2010.</p>

<h2 class="formal">
	We had the chance to ask Heumann some important questions about the progress we’ve made under the Obama administration, how you can get involved, and where we can go from here.<em> </em>Check out her answers below:&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="default">
	<strong>How did you first become involved with the disability rights movement?</strong></p>

<blockquote class="pullquote-1">
	"When I applied for my first job as a teacher, I was initially denied my certification simply because I could not walk."</blockquote>

<p>
	As a child, I, like more than 1 million other American children with disabilities, did not have the benefit of attending inclusive schools.&nbsp;Although access to quality education is critical to an individual’s future employment prospects, we were not allowed to attend school. I was nine years old before I went to school and even then I was placed in classes only for disabled children.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	Although I later attended university and earned my Bachelor’s degree, levels of inaccessibility prevalent at that time made it clear that employment was not something our government anticipated we would have.&nbsp;When I applied for my first job as a teacher, I was initially denied my certification simply because I could not walk.&nbsp;I went to court and sued the Board of Education to obtain my certificate to teach, and finally did get a job teaching elementary school children.</p>

<p>
	As a person with a significant disability who uses a motorized wheelchair and is able to travel extensively, I have been able to set an example to others in the U.S. and around the world about what it is possible to achieve. I learned from my parents early on that I have to have high expectations, and as a result I don&#039;t take no for an answer.&nbsp; By sharing those high expectations with other people, together we&#039;ve been able to really make dramatic changes here and around the world.</p>

<p>
	<strong>What are some ways you have worked to improve rights, equality, and inclusion for persons with disabilities as the Special Advisor for International Disability Rights and why is this role so important?</strong></p>

<p>
	The Department of State conducts our nation&#039;s foreign relations, engaging not only with foreign governments, but also with media, universities, business, and civil society.&nbsp;We address a broad range of global issues, including human rights, and I have used my time as Special Advisor to expand disability rights-related work across the Department of State and integrate that into our human rights diplomacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	We secured policy guidance on the importance of promoting disability inclusive diplomacy as a key part of U.S. foreign policy from Secretaries Clinton and Kerry.&nbsp;Our Foreign Service, Civil Service, and Locally Employed Staff are more active than ever in addressing the breadth of disabilities and identifying human rights violations toward people with disabilities, including trafficking of and violence against people with disabilities.</p>

<p>
	I have engaged Chiefs of Mission about using disability rights to reach important audiences, and secured support for marking the 25th Anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) and related recognition events.&nbsp;As a result, we have more comprehensive reporting on human rights abuses faced by persons with disabilities in the congressionally mandated Country Reports on Human Rights Practices.&nbsp; We have worked with likeminded states to elevate disability rights work within APEC and OSCE.&nbsp;We also participated in securing critical references to persons with disabilities in the revised World Bank Safeguards, Sustainable Development Goals, and numerous UN General Assembly and Human Rights Council resolutions. &nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<strong>Was there a particular moment&nbsp;made you realize you wanted to work for this administration? </strong></p>

<p>
	I have had so many. One moment to highlight was President Obama&#039;s commitment that the U.S. ratify the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities.&nbsp;While the Senate failed to recommend that the President ratify the CRPD, the efforts of his administration never faltered.&nbsp;He believes that laws like the ADA, Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act, and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, are examples of why the U.S. is a world leader in removing barriers and discrimination on the basis of disability.&nbsp;He is still committed to the ratification, and I do hope that the next Congress will recognize the importance of our ratification and act accordingly.</p>

<p>
	<strong>How have you seen this administration move the ball forward?</strong></p>

<p>
	In 2010, President Obama issued Executive Order 13548, which calls upon federal government departments and agencies to improve recruitment, hiring, retention, and advancement of persons with disabilities.&nbsp;Government agencies developed plans and published statistics on progress toward achieving the goals of the Executive Order.&nbsp;In 2012, total permanent employment in the federal government for persons with disabilities had increased to 11.89 piercent, with more people with disabilities in federal service both in real terms and by percentage than at any time in the past 32 years.</p>

<p>
	In the State Department, I am also encouraged by the increase in the number of new hires with disabilities.&nbsp;The support of Secretaries Clinton and Kerry has been instrumental in making this progress. The Department this year created the Office of Accessibility &amp; Accommodations to strengthen our ongoing provision of reasonable accommodations for employees with disabilities, and increase access to physical and virtual workspaces.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<strong>What are some of the challenges you have faced?</strong></p>

<blockquote class="pullquote-1">
	"The World Bank estimates that there are 1 billion people -- 15 percent of the world’s population -- with disabilities."</blockquote>

<p>
	Integrating disability rights into the Department’s human rights work has been a welcome challenge, and much has been accomplished in my six and a half years as the Special Advisor.&nbsp;The position of the Special Advisor is in itself an achievement – putting the issues of disability rights on the map, on the agenda for our work in bilateral and multilateral settings.&nbsp;We have worked office by office, bureau by bureau in Washington, and with our diplomatic missions overseas, to show how the U.S. record on disability rights and our advocacy for raising standards internationally can be a powerful tool for U.S. global leadership.&nbsp;I have tried to lead by example, and have benefited from the President’s personal commitment to inclusion as well as cooperation throughout the Department.</p>

<p>
	The World Bank estimates that there are 1 billion people --&nbsp;15 percent of the world’s population --&nbsp;with disabilities.&nbsp;That is why efforts such as the UN Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities are vital.&nbsp;Over 165 countries have signed on to the convention, and I am looking forward to additional ratifications, including by the United States.&nbsp; We have found, in our activities worldwide, that the CRPD has increased the empowerment of persons with disabilities and expanded disability rights movements. The State Department has increased its engagement with these groups, supporting the development of vibrant organizations within broader civil society. &nbsp;This role is key to moving beyond the signature and ratification stage to the more important tasks of enacting implementing legislation and enforcing policies and standards that protect the rights of persons with disabilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<strong>What do you see as the future of the disability rights movement both here at home and abroad?</strong></p>

<p>
	When we talk about disabled people and the disability rights movement, it is very important to keep in mind the broad range of people including those of us with physical disabilities as well as those with developmental, intellectual, or psychosocial disabilities. All disabled people have the right to enjoy our human rights on an equal basis with others in all areas of our lives, including in our access to education, employment, and the ability to participate as full citizens in our respective societies.</p>

<p>
	I would also ask that we --&nbsp;all of us, not just people in the disability rights community --&nbsp;look at issues through a lens of disability, rather than looking at specific issues separately, or as only issues for the disabled community.&nbsp;And by that, I mean that we need to look at how cross-cutting issues impact persons with disabilities --&nbsp;not for special treatment, but because the way we approach them for the disabled community can help inform the approach we take for everyone.</p>

<p>
	For example, how we protect the rights of disabled victims of violence can improve how we protect all those who are vulnerable to violence.&nbsp; Improving educational and health care services, and training of professionals for services to persons with disabilities, can improve institutional capacity for all citizens, both now and into the future.&nbsp;In the area of accessibility, breaking barriers provides opportunities to those individuals who have difficulty walking, or who may have baby carriages, or who may have shopping carts or are carrying things that are heavy.&nbsp;Ramps on corners help everyone.&nbsp;Accessible buses and accessible trains help people all over the world, and accessible buildings --&nbsp;including accessible bathrooms, things having Braille on them --&nbsp;that helps everyone also. &nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<strong>How can Americans help advance human rights for persons with disabilities and get involved as advocates in their communities this International Day of Persons with Disabilities?</strong></p>

<blockquote class="pullquote-1">
	"I have also observed that when disabled people from other countries come to the United States, when they leave the United States, one of the things they say is how they don’t feel different, regardless of their disability."</blockquote>

<p>
	As the world becomes smaller through globalization, it is critically important that the U.S. exercise its hard-earned leadership in expanding the recognition of the rights of disabled individuals.&nbsp;Ratification of the UN Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (CRPD), among its benefits, will help veterans and civilians have equal opportunities overseas to what their non-disabled peers have, such as the ability to study abroad, the ability to travel abroad, and the ability to work abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	I have also observed that when disabled people from other countries come to the United States, when they leave the United States, one of the things they say is how they don’t feel different, regardless of their disability.&nbsp;They feel that they can move around the community, that they’re not disenfranchised from being here.&nbsp;And I think that’s a very positive thing to say, that our laws, when effectively implemented over time, not only are removing physical barriers and barriers in other areas, but through the removal of these barriers are enabling people to come together across the country and really value each other for who we are, not for our sexual preference, our race, disability, et cetera. Most people, of course, are not engaged in international diplomacy, but are active in their home communities doing what they can to respond to&nbsp;the concerns of persons with disabilities.</p>

<p>
	I would ask that people take opportunities --&nbsp;not only on December 3, as this is a 365-day-a-year challenge --&nbsp;to listen to their fellow citizens with disabilities, and work with them to find and advance solutions.&nbsp;This is what has made the U.S. a strong model for disability rights advocates around the world, and we can do more to strengthen that model, working together.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<em>Jazmin Kay is an intern in the Office of Digital Strategy.&nbsp;</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Jazmin Kay </dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Address: Pass the 21st Century Cures Act</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/03/weekly-address-pass-21st-century-cures-act</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	In this week&#039;s address, President Obama highlighted the 21st Century Cures Act, a bill in Congress that could help us find a cure for Alzheimer&#039;s, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cancermoonshot">end cancer</a> as we know it, and help those who are seeking treatment for <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/opioids">opioid addiction</a>.This week, the House passed the bill overwhelmingly with bipartisan support --&nbsp;and the President called on the Senate to do the same when they vote in a few days. Because that&#039;s what this is all about: coming to a compromise based on the belief that we should seize every chance we have to find cures as soon as possible.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_iKNE4ndBdg?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/03/weekly-address-pass-21st-century-cures-act">Transcript</a> | <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/videos/2016/December/20161203_POTUS_Weekly_Address_HD.mp4">MP4</a> | <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/videos/2016/December/20161203_POTUS_Weekly_Address.mp3">MP3</a></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/melanie-garunay&quot;&gt;Melanie Garunay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Wing Week 12/1/16 or, &amp;quot;Push a Button and It&amp;#039;s Electrified!&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/02/west-wing-week-12116-or-push-button-and-its-electrified-0</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	The holidays have arrived!&nbsp;It&#039;s been a busy here in the White House as we get ready for the holiday season - from First Lady, Michelle Obama receiving the Official White House Christmas tree, to her welcoming military families to the White House to preview the holiday decorations, to President Obama meeting with the 2016 American Nobel Peace Prize winners, to the First Family closing out the week by attending the National Christmas Tree Lighting. Get into the holiday spirit and watch this week’s episode of West Wing Week.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/TiuTu90IKJs?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	On Friday, First Lady, Michelle Obama received the official White House Christmas Tree, joined by her nephews.</p>

<p>
	<span style="color:rgb(67, 67, 67); font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt; letter-spacing:0.1pt"><div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/q_bt7xzp8og?0=size%3D%22large%E2%80%9D&version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></span></p>

<p>
	On Tuesday, First Lady, Michelle Obama unveiled the 2016 holiday decorations and welcomed military families to the White House as part of her Joining Forces initiative.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/k6_1r52WplI?0=size%3D%22large%E2%80%9D&version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	On Wednesday, President Obama welcomed the 2016 American Nobel Peace Prize recipients&nbsp;Dr. F. Duncan Haldane, Dr. Oliver Hart, Dr. J. Michael Kosterlitz, and Sir J. Fraser Stoddart,&nbsp;to the Oval Office.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nk9aAt5khFk?0=size%3D%22large%E2%80%9D&version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	Thursday, President Obama<a href="http://twitter.com/WhiteHouse/status/804407965704929280"> commerated World AIDS Day by honoring those who are leading the fight against HIV and AIDS</a>.</p>

<p>
	<img alt="POTUS Aids Day" height="537" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Capture3_1.PNG" width="582" /></p>

<p>
	Later in the evening, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FBYlc3dLkBU">the First Family attended the National Christmas Tree Lighting held at the Ellipse</a>. The holiday celebration was hosted by Eva Longoria and featured a line-up of performances by Yolanda Adams, The Lumineers, Chance the Rapper, Kelly Clarkson, Garth Brooks, Trisha Yearwood,&nbsp;March Anthony, Afro Blue, James Taylor, and the Airmen of Note.</p>

<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="Yolanda Adams performs during the National Christmas Tree lighting on the Ellipse in Washington, D.C., Dec. 1, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Lawrence Jackson)" height="1333" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/P120116LJ-0539.jpg" width="2000" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 2000px;">
		Yolanda Adams performs during the National Christmas Tree lighting on the Ellipse in Washington, D.C., Dec. 1, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Lawrence Jackson)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="President Barack Obama, First Lady Michelle Obama and daughter Sasha join performers on stage to sing &quot;Jingle Bells&quot; during the National Christmas Tree lighting event on the Ellipse in Washington, D.C., Dec. 1, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)" height="1333" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/P120116PS-0981.jpg" width="2000" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 2000px;">
		President Barack Obama, First Lady Michelle Obama and daughter Sasha join performers on stage to sing "Jingle Bells" during the National Christmas Tree lighting event on the Ellipse in Washington, D.C., Dec. 1, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	<em>Crystal Miller is an intern for the Office of Digital Strategy. </em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 17:05:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Crystal Miller </dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for TechHire</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/02/whats-next-techhire</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	The premise behind the TechHire initiative is simple: Give more people the skills they need to succeed in the tech jobs that employers are struggling to fill. The initiative started with 21 cities, states, and rural areas from St. Louis to Eastern Kentucky, teaming up with 300 companies to train and source a diverse tech workforce from atypical backgrounds. As U.S. Chief Technology Officer Megan Smith puts it, these communities are tapping into talent that was previously “hiding in plain sight.”</p>

<p>
	Nearly two years later, TechHire has grown to over 70 communities, 20 of which launched yesterday. Nearly 4,000 people have been placed into jobs paying well above the average private-sector median wage. Companies like GE Digital, JP Morgan, and Capital One are hiring talent based on candidates’ demonstrated abilities, rather than the names on their degrees.</p>

<p>
	What we have learned from these communities is that people can learn the skills they need to succeed in tech jobs in a matter of months, not years. And with nearly 600,000 open technology jobs across all industries and regions in the country today, we need to continue spreading these models to meet the demand.</p>

<p>
	That’s why the TechHire initiative was designed to rely on communities across the country coming together to take coordinated action that leverages existing funding. TechHire communities have been using funds that the federal government already spends on job training and reemployment services. &nbsp;To make sure we can build on that progress, the U.S. Department of Education announced a partnership this week with Opportunity@Work to continue growing the TechHire network.</p>

<p>
	The growth and success of TechHire will come from the same source it has to date: grassroots partners. These employers, innovative training programs, local government, workforce development organizations, and others in communities are collaborating to push the boundaries of the status quo, using strategies such as:</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		<strong>Hiring based on skill, not pedigree:</strong> Giving people the chance to get hired based on what they show they can actually do, rather than what’s listed on a resume;</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Training in months, not years:</strong> Training people with the skills to get entry-level tech jobs in months-long immersive and on-the-job training, rather than four years at a university;</li>
	<li>
		<strong>A “pay for success” training model: </strong>Creating training programs with sufficiently high returns (based on increased wages) such that the training provider or a third-party investor would be willing to bear the up-front risks associated with the program;</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Broadening the circle of opportunity:</strong> Fostering opportunities for adults to get on a pathway to the middle class regardless of where they start, including low-income Americans, minorities, veterans, and the long-term unemployed.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<h2 class="semibold">
	Here’s more on what’s happening around the country.</h2>

<p>
	<strong>Akron, Ohio</strong></p>

<figure class="image-captioned image-right">
	<img alt="William" height="193" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/William_0.jpg" width="200" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 200px;">
		William</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	Since Akron joined the TechHire initiative, over 250 students have graduated from local training partners, more than half of whom have been placed into full-time jobs with 75 companies, with an average starting salary of $52,000. To improve connections between graduates that need jobs and employers that need tech talent, TechHire Akron will participate in the national “Race to Place” pilot hiring platform, coordinated by Opportunity@Work. This pilot will give employers a way to identify and assess potential tech talent, and help graduates to find “good-fit” job opportunities.<br />
	William is one of the people who has benefited from Akron’s work. William was making $12 an hour when he decided to pursue an intensive, 12-week coding bootcamp with the Software Guild in Akron. Of the experience, he later said, “there were plenty of times when I thought I would not make it, but I fought through it.” After graduating, he landed a job as a computer programmer, with a starting salary of $50,000 and the opportunity to continue growing his tech skills. He has since been promoted.</p>

<p>
	<strong>Colorado</strong></p>

<figure class="image-captioned image-right">
	<img alt="Jessey" height="200" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/Jessey_0.jpg" width="200" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 200px;">
		Jessey</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	In Colorado, partner organizations have reported over 1,000 individuals trained with tech skills since TechHire Colorado first launched as one of the original TechHire communities. The vast majority of TechHire graduates in Colorado have found full-time tech jobs in a variety of industries.</p>

<p>
	Jessey Eagan is one such individual. Jessey was once a second-grade teacher and a children&#039;s director at church, interested to make a career change. Seeking opportunity, she picked up her family and moved from Illinois to Colorado for a 10-week intensive coding bootcamp with RefactorU. In the end, her family&#039;s sacrifice was worth it: Jessey now works full-time as a quality assurance web automation engineer at MakeMusic.</p>

<p>
	Given the success stories of existing TechHire communities, it came as no surprise that more communities sought to participate in the initiative. As a result, this week we announced over 20 additional new communities that will invest in and scale strategies that work.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<strong>Boston, Massachusetts</strong></p>

<figure class="image-captioned image-right">
	<img alt="Brian" height="301" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/Brian.jpg" width="200" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 200px;">
		Brian</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	Boston is one of the communities that signed on to TechHire this week. In Boston, a regional consortium of employers and training providers are blazing the path to IT jobs, led by the Boston Private Industry Council (PIC), the City’s workforce development board, and SkillWorks, a regional funders’ collaborative. Companies from a range of sectors -- including healthcare, education, government, technology, and finance -- will help develop training and hiring pipelines for the skills they need. Through TechHire, Boston plans to more than double the number of high school Tech Apprentices from 100 to 250 and increase the number of individuals connected to IT-related jobs to 500 by 2020.</p>

<p>
	One of Boston’s early success stories is that of Brian Madrigal, a young Mexican-American man from East Boston. Relentlessly optimistic and hardworking, Brian enrolled in Resilient Coders, a local program for young people to learn to code. Today, Brian is a User Experience apprentice at Fresh Tilled Soil, one of the most prestigious design agencies in Boston.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	<strong>Tulsa, Oklahoma</strong></p>

<figure class="image-captioned image-right">
	<img alt="Preston" height="223" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/Preston_1.jpg" width="200" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 200px;">
		Preston</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	The tech scene in Tulsa, OK is already growing, with support from local organizations including 36 Degrees North, Techlahoma, and a number of workforce and education partners. With strong backing from the Mayor’s Office, Tulsa decided to apply for TechHire, with a plan to train and place 600 people—with an emphasis on women and young people—into tech jobs across sectors by 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	The community’s enthusiasm for tech training is based on stories like that of Preston Schwartz. Preston was a hard-working mechanic, in a physically demanding job with little room for upward mobility. Seeking new opportunity, he enrolled in a local OK Coders class to learn software development. Impressed by Preston’s progress over the 10-week boot camp, one of his teachers offered him a job as a Junior Front End Developer for his company, Hire 360. In that role, Preston is able to better provide for his family and to continue to grow his coding skills.</p>

<p>
	<strong>Rhode Island</strong></p>

<figure class="image-captioned image-right">
	<img alt="Nick" height="200" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/Nick.jpg" width="200" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 200px;">
		Nick</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	TechHire Rhode Island (TechHireRI) joined the TechHire network in late 2015. This statewide initiative is partnering closely with Governor Raimondo, CommerceRI, the RI Department of Labor and Training, and many education and training partners, on a goal to place 2,000 Rhode Islanders into IT jobs by 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	In 2016, TechHireRI has grown to include nearly 200 employer partners. Its education partners have trained about 250 people, about 200 of whom have been placed in IT and software developer positions. To expand access to training, TechHireRI has worked with training partners LaunchCode and General Assembly to stand up a full scholarship program for accelerated coding courses, which benefits nearly 250 Rhode Islanders. And so far this fall, GE Digital has hired one-third of the staff in its new office in Providence through TechHireRI.</p>

<p>
	One of the new GE Digital hires is Nick Wilcox. Nick’s job as a strength coach offered little room for growth, so he began experimenting with web development -- for fun and with zero formal training. He was intrigued with trying something radically new, failing, then trying again, and before long, decided to make a career out of it. He enrolled in General Assembly’s Web Development Immersive, which was not only more affordable than a traditional degree, but quicker -- 12 weeks, as compared to four years. And today, he’s a front-end developer with a significantly higher salary than what he was earning as a trainer.</p>

<p>
	<em>Ryan Burke, Special Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ryan Burke</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Employment Situation in November</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/12/02/employment-situation-november</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<em>The economy added a solid 178,000 jobs in November as the longest streak of total job growth on record continued. U.S. businesses have now added 15.6 million jobs since early 2010. The unemployment rate fell to 4.6 percent in November, its lowest level since August 2007, and the broadest measure of underemployment fell for the second month in a row. Average hourly earnings for private employees have increased at an annual rate of 2.7 percent so far in 2016, faster than the pace of inflation. Nevertheless, more work remains to ensure that the benefits of the recovery are broadly shared, including </em><em>opening new markets to </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/docs/cea_trade_report_final_non-embargoed_v2.pdf"><em>U.S. exports</em></a><em>; taking steps to spur </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/10/25/fact-sheet-obama-administration-announces-new-steps-spur-competition"><em>competition</em></a><em> to benefit consumers, workers, and entrepreneurs; and </em><em>raising the </em><a href="http://voxeu.org/article/minimum-wage-increases-and-earnings-low-wage-jobs" target="_blank"><em>minimum wage</em></a><em>.</em></p>

<p>
	<strong>FIVE KEY POINTS ON THE LABOR MARKET IN NOVEMBER 2016</strong></p>

<p>
	<strong>1. U.S. businesses have now added 15.6 million jobs since private-sector job growth turned positive in early 2010.</strong> Today, we learned that private employment rose by 156,000 jobs in November. Total nonfarm employment rose by 178,000 jobs, in line with the monthly average for 2016 so far and substantially higher than the pace of about 80,000 jobs per month that CEA estimates is necessary to maintain a low and stable unemployment rate given the impact of demographic trends on labor force participation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	In November, the unemployment rate fell to 4.6 percent, its lowest level since August 2007. The labor force participation rate ticked down, though it is largely unchanged over the last three years (see point 3 below). The U-6 rate, the broadest official measure of labor underutilization fell 0.2 percentage point for the second month in a row in part due to a reduction in the number of employees working part-time for economic reasons. (The U-6 rate is the only official measure of underutilization that has not already fallen below its pre-recession average.) So far in 2016, nominal hourly earnings for private-sector workers have increased at an annual rate of 2.7 percent, faster than the pace of inflation (1.6 percent as of October, the most recent data available).</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Private-Sector Payroll Employment" height="660" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Charts/chart1_JOBS_pspayrollemp.png" width="910" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>2. New <a href="http://voxeu.org/article/minimum-wage-increases-and-earnings-low-wage-jobs" target="_blank"><strong>CEA analysis</strong></a> finds that State minimum wage increases since 2013 contributed to substantial wage increases for workers in low-wage jobs, with no discernible impact on employment. </strong>In his 2013 State of the Union address, President Obama called on Congress to raise the Federal minimum wage, which has remained at $7.25 an hour since 2009. Even as Congress has failed to act, 18 States and the District of Columbia—along with dozens of local government jurisdictions—have answered the President’s call to action and have raised their minimum wages. (In addition to the States that have already raised their minimum wages, voters in four States approved measures to raise the minimum wage in November.) To assess the impact of minimum wage increases implemented by States in recent years, CEA analyzed data from the payroll survey for workers in the leisure and hospitality industry—a group who tend to earn lower wages than those in other major industry groups and thus are most likely to be affected by changes in the minimum wage. As the chart below shows, hourly earnings grew substantially faster for leisure and hospitality workers in States that raised their minimum wages than in States that did not. By comparing trends in wage growth for the two groups, CEA estimates that increases in the minimum wage led to an increase of roughly 6.6 percent in average wages for these workers. At the same time—consistent with a large body of economic research that has tended to find <a href="http://research.upjohn.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1220&amp;context=empl_research" target="_blank">little or no impact</a> of past minimum wage increases on employment—leisure and hospitality employment followed virtually identical trends in States that did and did not raise their minimum wage since 2013. (See <a href="http://voxeu.org/article/minimum-wage-increases-and-earnings-low-wage-jobs" target="_blank">here</a> for more details on CEA’s analysis.)</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Average Hourly Earnings, Leisure and Hospitality" height="662" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Charts/chart2a_JOBS_avghrlyearnLH.png" width="911" /></p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Total Employment, Leisure and Hospitality " height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Charts/chart2b_JOBS_totalempymntLH.png" width="910" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>3. The strengthening labor market is drawing individuals into the labor force, offsetting downward pressure on employment growth from the aging of the population. </strong>Employment growth depends on three factors: population growth, the rate at which the population participates in the labor force, and the share of the labor force that is employed. The chart below decomposes employment growth (from the household survey) into contributions from each of these factors for each year of the current recovery. It further decomposes labor force participation into shifts attributable to demographics (such as the aging of the U.S. population) and shifts attributable to other factors (such as the business cycle). Throughout the recovery, demographic changes in labor force participation—primarily driven by a large increase in retirement by baby boomers that began in 2008—have consistently weighed on employment growth. In recent years, however, non-demographic changes in labor force participation have supported employment growth, as the strengthening of the labor market and increasing real wages have drawn more individuals into the labor force. The entry (or reentry) of workers into the labor force has helped employment growth maintain its recent solid pace even as the unemployment rate has fallen more slowly. These two shifts in labor force participation—demographic and non-demographic—have largely offset one another in recent months, and as a result the overall labor force participation rate has remained broadly stable since the end of 2013.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Decomposition of Employment Growth in the Recovery " height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Charts/chart3_JOBS_decompempgrowth.png" width="911" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>4. The number of unemployed workers per job opening, an indicator of labor market slack, is near its lowest level prior to the recession.</strong> Using data from the household survey and the Job Openings and Labor Turnover Survey, the chart below plots the ratio of unemployed workers to total job openings. In the recession, unemployment rose rapidly while job openings plummeted, sending the ratio of unemployed workers to job openings to a record peak of 6.6 in July 2009. As the unemployment rate has decreased over the course of the recovery, and as job openings have climbed to record highs this year, the ratio of unemployed workers to openings has fallen steeply, standing at 1.4 as of September (the most recent data available for openings). This is close to the ratio’s lowest level in the 2000s expansion, another indicator—in addition to recent increases in real wages—of a strengthening labor market.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Unemployed Workers per Job Opening, 2001-2016" height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Charts/chart4_JOBS_unemplyworkersopening.png" width="911" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>5. The distribution of job growth across industries in November diverged from the pattern over the past year. </strong>Above-average gains relative to the past year were seen in professional and business services (+49,000, excluding temporary help services), while mining and logging (which includes oil extraction) posted a gain (+2,000) for the second time in recent months amid moderation in oil prices. On the other hand, retail trade (-8,000), information services (-10,000), and financial activities (+6,000) all saw weaker-than-average growth. Slow global growth has continued to weigh on the manufacturing sector, which is more export-oriented than other industries and which posted a loss of 4,000 jobs in November. Across the 17 industries shown below, the correlation between the most recent one-month percent change and the average percent change over the last twelve months was -0.06, the lowest level since September 2012.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Employment Growth by Industry " height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Charts/chart5_JOBS_empgrowthindstry.png" width="910" /></p>

<p>
	<em>As the Administration stresses every month, the monthly employment and unemployment figures can be volatile, and payroll employment estimates can be subject to substantial revision. Therefore, it is important not to read too much into any one monthly report, and it is informative to consider each report in the context of other data as they become available.</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/jason-furman&quot;&gt;Jason Furman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to See the White House on a Dollar Bill</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/30/how-see-white-house-dollar-bill</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p class="rtecenter">
	<strong>Get the 1600 app now to experience the White House in augmented reality.</strong></p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/v3e_RM-QsXk?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p class="rtecenter">
	<span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-green" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/1600/id1179840697?mt=8" target="_blank">IOS</a></span></span></span></span></span>&nbsp;&nbsp; <span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><span class="linkbox" data-widget="linkbox"><a class="linkbox-title btn btn-green" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.whha.sixteenhundred" target="_blank">Android</a></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<hr />
<p>
	What’s it like to attend a state dinner at the White House? Or see Marine One land on the South Lawn?</p>

<p>
	From hosting festivals on the South Lawn to allowing people to explore its rooms via Google Street View, President Obama has used traditional events and new technology to open up the doors of the White House to more Americans than ever before.</p>

<p>
	Today, we’re excited to share a new way for you to experience 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue -- and all you need is a smartphone and a dollar bill.</p>

<p>
	<span contenteditable="false" tabindex="-1"><img alt="Watch the White House appear on a one dollar bill with the new 1600 app." height="854" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/WhiteHouseAR2.png" width="1280" /></span></p>

<p>
	Check it out now: Download the app, point your smartphone camera at a dollar bill, and you’ll see an interactive, 3D video of White House pop up – narrated by yours truly.</p>

<p>
	As you experience a year at the White House – from the Easter Egg Roll to a State Arrival Ceremony – you’ll see that even as seasons and people change, the White House endures as an institution of American democracy. That’s why we teamed up with the White House Historical Association and Nexus Studios to create this augmented reality experience <span style="color:rgb(67, 67, 67); font-family:arial,helvetica,nimbus sans l,sans-serif; letter-spacing:0.13px">–</span> to educate and inspire Americans to learn all about what the People’s House stands for.</p>

<p>
	Whether it’s seen on a teacher&#039;s desk or around a dining room table, we hope you enjoy and share this new way of taking a peek inside the White House.</p>

<p>
	So, give it a try: If you have an iPhone or iPad, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/1600/id1179840697?mt=8">you can download 1600 here.</a> Or if you have an Android phone or Android tablet, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.whha.sixteenhundred">you can get it here.</a></p>

<p>
	Check it out!</p>

<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/josh-earnest&quot;&gt;Josh Earnest&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#039;s Next for Criminal Justice Reform</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/30/whats-next-criminal-justice-reform</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<em>U.S. Senator Cory Booker sent the following message to the White House email list ahead of a White House convening on criminal justice reform. You can tune in below at 2:30pm ET:</em></p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZuD7T8ymz7E?autoplay=1&version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<hr />
<p>
	If someone had pulled aside the signers of the Declaration of Independence 240 years ago and told them that, one day, the country they founded would be home to the largest number of imprisoned people in the world, they might have been more than a little disappointed.</p>

<p>
	Yet this is where we find our country today: The United States, founded on the basis of liberty and justice for all, suffers from that distinction. Twenty five percent of all imprisoned people on our planet are imprisoned right here in America. And the fact of the matter is that, at the federal level, the majority of those imprisoned aren’t hardened, violent prisoners. Far too many are nonviolent, low-level drug offenders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	Thanks to policies enacted by Congress, our federal prison population has exploded by nearly 800 percent over the past the 30 years. And to pay for it, we’ve had to increase our prison spending by almost 400 percent. But the fact that these polices were enacted by our government in the first place should serve as a reminder that we have the agency to change them.</p>

<p>
	Momentum is building across America -- in states, in the federal government, in both political parties -- to change this misapplication of justice that so grossly misrepresents our priorities as a nation.</p>

<p>
	A diverse coalition of individuals, groups, and organizations -- ranging from Democrats to Republicans to law enforcement officials and clergy -- have come together to call for a comprehensive change in the trajectory of our justice system. And under President Obama’s leadership, the collective vision of these groups has found a home and a voice in the White House.</p>

<p>
	I have been proud to stand by President Obama as he has taken courageous steps in recent years to make our justice system more just.</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/11/30/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-new-commitments-fair-chance-business">Today, the White House is announcing that over 300 companies and organizations have signed the Fair Chance Business Pledge</a>, a commitment to eliminate unnecessary hiring barriers facing people with a criminal record. Along with this step and a series of Administrative actions to enhance the fairness and effectiveness of the criminal justice system, he’s shown that the federal government can lead the way to progress.</p>

<p>
	President Obama has created a legacy of bold action that we must carry on to elevate the cause of criminal justice reform, from Congress to statehouses across the country.</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/issues/criminal-justice-reform">Learn more about what’s at stake in the effort to reform our broken criminal justice system:</a> Make sure to check out the White House discussion today, where a coalition of leaders and activists will join together to discuss what’s next for criminal justice reform.</p>

<p>
	But the conversation can’t stop there, and neither can the work. We must once again declare that we are a nation of independence, rooted in the spirit of interdependence. What happens to any of us, happens to all of us -- and we won’t get where we want to go faster by leaving anyone behind.</p>

<p>
	I look forward to standing shoulder to shoulder with you in this fight to reclaim our criminal justice system in the years to come.</p>

<p>
	Thank you,</p>

<p>
	Cory Booker</p>

<p>
	U.S. Senator</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Senator Cory Booker</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Obama’s Top Ten Actions to Accelerate American Entrepreneurship</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/30/president-obamas-top-ten-actions-accelerate-american-entrepreneurship</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="President Barack Obama hosts White House Demo Day, which celebrates the role entrepreneurship plays in America&#039;s economy, in the State Dining Room of the White House, Aug. 4, 2015. The President discusses the Partpic replacement part exhibit with Jewel Burks and Jason Crain from Atlanta, Ga. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)" height="613" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/P080415PS-0570.jpeg" width="920" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 920px;">
		President Barack Obama hosts White House Demo Day, which celebrates the role entrepreneurship plays in America&#039;s economy, in the State Dining Room of the White House, Aug. 4, 2015. The President discusses the Partpic replacement part exhibit with Jewel Burks and Jason Crain from Atlanta, Ga. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	America’s entrepreneurial economy is the envy of the world.&nbsp; Young companies account for almost 30 percent of new jobs, and as we’ve fought back from the worst economic crisis of our lifetimes, startups have helped our private sector create <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/04/employment-situation-october">15.5 million jobs</a> since early 2010—the longest streak of private-sector job creation on record.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	Today, in celebration of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/10/31/presidential-proclamation-national-entrepreneurship-month-2016">National Entrepreneurship Month</a>, the Administration is releasing a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/11/30/fact-sheet-celebrating-president-obamas-top-10-actions-advance">Top 10 list</a> of President Obama’s most significant specific actions to promote American entrepreneurship, as well as announcing new efforts to build on these successes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	Over the past eight years, thanks to the grit, determination, and creativity of entrepreneurs all across the country, American startup activity is rebounding and growing more inclusive.</p>

<p>
	<img alt="President Obama has taken action to accelerate American Entrepreneurship" height="464" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/entrepreneurship-04.jpg" width="920" /></p>

<p>
	<img alt="Between 2007 and 2016 the number of women-owned firms grew at an estimated 5 times faster than the national average and the number of minority-owned firms more than doubled. " height="463" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/entrepreneurship-02.jpg" width="920" /></p>

<p>
	<img alt="The number of startup accelerator programs increased from fewer than 30 in 2009 to over 170 in 2015, providing mentorship and early funding to thousands of startups across 35 states plus D.C. and 54 metro areas" height="465" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/entrepreneurship-03.jpg" width="920" /></p>

<p>
	Here is a short summary of the President’s top 10 actions to accelerate American entrepreneurship; for more details, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/11/30/fact-sheet-celebrating-president-obamas-top-10-actions-advance"><strong>see here</strong></a>.</p>

<ol>
	<li>
		<strong>Signed permanent tax incentives for startup investment,</strong> by making the research and experimentation (R&amp;E) tax credit available to pre-revenue startups and permanently eliminating capital gains tax on certain small business investments.</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Accelerated the transition of research discoveries from lab to market, </strong>by scaling up the I-Corps entrepreneurship training program for Federally-funded scientists and engineers, opening up data on Federal research facilities and intellectual property, extending and strengthening the $2.5 billion<strong> </strong>Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR)&nbsp;program, and more.</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Cut red tape for entrepreneurs, with </strong>over 100 cities and communities taking the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/08/04/startup-day-four-things-you-should-know">Startup in a Day</a> pledge to streamline their business startup processes, allowing entrepreneurs to navigate requirements in as little as 24 hours.</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Expanded regional entrepreneurship opportunities,&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.sba.gov/offices/headquarters/ooi/resources/1428931">startup accelerator </a><a href="https://www.sba.gov/offices/headquarters/ooi/resources/1428931">programs</a>&nbsp;investing in <a href="https://www.sba.gov/about-sba/sba-initiatives/clusters-initiative">regional innovation clusters</a>, and incentivizing <a href="https://www.eda.gov/oie/ris/">regional innovation strategies</a> research commercialization centers and early-stage seed capital funds.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Directly boosted entrepreneurs’ access to capital, </strong>with $8.4 billion in loans and venture investments catalyzed by the <a href="https://www.treasury.gov/resource-center/sb-programs/Documents/SSBCI%20Program%20Evaluation%202016%20-%20Full%20Report.pdf">State Small Business Credit Initiative (SSBCI)</a> and new pathways for impact investment funds and early-stage innovation funds through the <a href="https://www.sba.gov/sbic">Small Business Investment Company (SBIC)</a> program.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Prioritized inclusive entrepreneurship, with the </strong>first-ever <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2015/08/04/fact-sheet-president-obama-announces-new-commitments-investors-companies">White House Demo Day</a> catalyzing major investors, technology companies, and other organizations to committing to new actions to ensure diverse recruitment and hiring, complemented by Federal agency actions to reduce barriers faced by women entrepreneurs, train veteran entrepreneurs for 21st century opportunities, and more.</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Created opportunities for promising entrepreneurs and innovators from abroad, </strong>allowing international students with qualifying science and engineering degrees from U.S. universities to extend the time they participate in practical training, and unlocking the talents of high-skilled Americans-in-waiting.</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Updated <strong>securities laws for high-growth companies, </strong></strong>with the bipartisan <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/06/08/promise-crowdfunding-and-american-innovation">Jumpstart Our Business Startups (JOBS) Act</a> making it easier for smaller firms to responsibly make an initial public offering (IPO), allowing entrepreneurs to raise up to $50 million through regulated “mini public offerings,” and creating a national marketplace for securities-based crowdfunding.</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Made the U.S. patent system more efficient and responsive to innovators, by signing the </strong>bipartisan America Invents Act to significantly reduce patent application costs and wait times for startups and small businesses, taking steps to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/page/files/201603_patent_litigation_issue_brief_cea.pdf">increase transparency</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2013/06/04/fact-sheet-white-house-task-force-high-tech-patent-issues">level the playing field</a> for innovators, and more.</li>
	<li>
		<strong>Unleashed entrepreneurship in the industries of the future, </strong>including clean energy, biotechnology, the commercial space industry, nanotechnology, drones, robotics, advanced manufacturing, and more.</li>
</ol>

<p>
	To ensure that every American entrepreneur has a straight shot at success, we need all hands on deck.&nbsp; That’s why, since the launch of the White House <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2011/01/31/white-house-launch-startup-america-initiative">Startup America</a> initiative in 2011, the President has issued a consistent public call to action to companies, nonprofits, universities, investors, and others to celebrate and accelerate high-growth entrepreneurship throughout the country.</p>

<p>
	Today, even more organizations are responding to that call to action, with engineering deans from more than 200 universities committed to building a more diverse student talent pipeline; 79 companies committed to the Tech Inclusion Pledge, an effort to make the technology workforce at each of their companies representative of the American people as soon as possible; and over 30 angel investor groups with over $800 million under management making a new commitment to promote inclusive entrepreneurship.&nbsp;For more details, <strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/11/30/fact-sheet-celebrating-president-obamas-top-10-actions-advance">click here</a>.</strong></p>

<p>
	Many of President Obama’s signature achievements have significantly increased opportunities for entrepreneurs to take smart risks and build the next generation of great American companies:&nbsp; the Affordable Care Act is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2014/03/11/geeksgetcovered">making it easier for entrepreneurs to buy health insurance</a>, unlocking them from traditional employer-based coverage; the Pay As You Earn program is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/04/28/fact-sheet-taking-action-help-more-americans-manage-student-debt">making it easier for entrepreneurs to pay off student loan debt</a>; the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/09/28/fact-sheet-data-people-people-eight-years-progress-opening-government">Open Data Initiative</a> has unlocked over 200,000 government datasets as raw material for entrepreneurial innovation; <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/issues/education/k-12/connected">ConnectED</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/03/09/fact-sheet-president-obama-announces-connectall-initiative">ConnectALL</a> are allowing aspiring entrepreneurs everywhere to access high-speed broadband, while a strong <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/net-neutrality">net neutrality</a> policy ensures a free and open internet; and the President signed into law the largest annual increase in <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/06/21/impact-report-100-examples-president-obamas-leadership-science">research and development</a> funding in America’s history.</p>

<p>
	These and other efforts to address <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/04/13/president-obama-s-record-results-and-agenda-income-inequality">income inequality</a>, promote <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/04/15/executive-order-steps-increase-competition-and-better-inform-consumers">competitive markets</a>, reduce unduly restrictive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/06/17/fact-sheet-new-steps-reduce-unnecessary-occupation-licenses-are-limiting">occupational licensing</a>, and scale up <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/issues/technology/techhire">rapid training for 21st century technology skills</a> are essential to ensure that America remains the best place on the planet to start and scale the next great company.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 09:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/thomas-kalil&quot;&gt;Thomas Kalil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/doug-rand&quot;&gt;Doug Rand&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the Gift of the Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/29/celebrating-gift-holidays</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="Volunteers and staff work on holiday decorations in the Lower Cross Hall of the White House, Nov. 28, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)" height="1402" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/P112816CK-0047.jpg" width="2000" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 2000px;">
		Volunteers and staff work on holiday decorations in the Lower Cross Hall of the White House, Nov. 28, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	The smell of pine, the taste of gingerbread cookies, the choral sounds of music filling the halls and the sight of thousands of guests coming through the doors -- that’s right, it’s time for another magical holiday season at the White House!</p>

<p>
	In our eighth and final holiday season, we’re celebrating the theme, "The Gift of the Holidays" -- the gift of family and friends, reflection and remembrance, and excitement and cheer.</p>

<p>
	As the White House Social Secretary, it’s my job to lead the transformation of the People’s House during the holiday season and help welcome everyone who comes through the White House doors.</p>

<p>
	It all begins six months ahead of time with input from Mrs. Obama along with a talented team of designers who come up with amazing and festive concepts and sketches for the entire White House, the private residence, and the West Wing (including the Oval Office).</p>

<p>
	Then, we have the hard task of sorting through a bulk of eager, everyday citizens who want to volunteer to help us decorate. We read lots of fun and creative letters. The volunteers show up the Friday after Thanksgiving and work tirelessly with the designers, White House Executive Residence team, Social Office and so many others to get it all ready! It’s a team effort to bring it all together. We are so lucky that in addition to the tours and receptions to showcase the work, we are able to also bring the joyous experience of the Holidays to those online. You’ll be able to view all of the amazing décor soon, but here are&nbsp;just a few hints at what you’ll see.</p>

<p>
	We’ve moved the traditional military tribute to the East Garden Room to allow more space for guests to reflect and send messages to those serving abroad. As always, the Blue Room will hold the majestic, official White House Christmas tree -- along with the featuring key excerpts from the Constitution and images that represent the diversity of America. I won’t reveal much more, but be sure to look for your home state in the State Dining Room and get ready to have your wide-angle camera lens ready for the fun, larger than life display of the First Dogs, Bo and Sunny!</p>

<p>
	<img alt="Entrance to the Blue Room" height="1260" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/seal.jpg" width="900" /></p>

<p>
	It’s been my honor and privilege to work another year as the Social Secretary for President and Mrs. Obama. On behalf of the social office team -- Lauren Kelly, Elizabeth Pan, Pantea Faed, Kristina Broadie, Kayla Daniels, and Jonathan Lee -- we hope you enjoy the decorations as much as we enjoyed getting them ready for you.</p>

<p>
	Let the season begin!</p>

<p>
	<em>Deesha Dyer is the White House Social Secretary</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 09:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Deesha Dyer</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second Estimate of Gross Domestic Product for the Third Quarter of 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/29/second-estimate-gross-domestic-product-third-quarter-2016</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<em>Third-quarter economic growth was revised up 0.3 percentage point to 3.2 percent at an annual rate, a noticeably faster pace than in the first half of the year. Exports, which have faced substantial headwinds in recent years from slow growth abroad, grew at an annual rate of 10.1 percent in the third quarter, boosted in part by transitory factors. Consumer spending continued to grow at a solid pace in the third quarter, while inventory investment (one of the </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/07/29/advance-estimate-gross-domestic-product-second-quarter-2016"><em>most volatile</em></a><em> components of GDP) boosted GDP growth after subtracting from it in the prior five quarters. Third-quarter growth in the most stable and persistent components of output—consumption and fixed investment—was revised up to 2.1 percent. </em><em>Still, more work remains to strengthen economic growth and to ensure that it is broadly shared</em><em>, including </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/04/15/ending-rotary-rental-phones-thinking-outside-cable-box"><em>promoting greater competition</em></a><em> across the economy; </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/docs/ERP_2016_Chapter_5.pdf"><em>supporting innovation</em></a><em>; </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/docs/ERP_2016_Chapter_6.pdf"><em>increasing investments in infrastructure</em></a><em>; and </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/docs/cea_trade_report_final_non-embargoed_v2.pdf"><em>opening new markets to U.S. exports</em></a><em>.</em></p>

<p>
	<strong>FIVE KEY POINTS IN TODAY&#039;S REPORT FROM THE BUREAU OF ECONOMIC ANALYSIS (BEA)</strong></p>

<p>
	<strong>1. Real gross domestic product (GDP) increased 3.2 percent at an annual rate in the third quarter of 2016, according to BEA’s second estimate.</strong> Real consumer spending grew a solid 2.8 percent in the third quarter following its strong second-quarter growth of 4.3 percent, with robust growth in durable goods spending and a small contraction in nondurable goods spending. Inventory investment—one of the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/07/29/advance-estimate-gross-domestic-product-second-quarter-2016">most volatile</a> components of GDP—added 0.5 percentage point to GDP growth in the third quarter after subtracting 1.2 percentage point in the second quarter. Residential investment declined for the second quarter in a row, though at a slower pace in the third quarter than in the second. Notably, exports grew 10.1 percent at an annual rate in the third quarter, its fastest quarterly growth since late 2013, boosted by a jump in agricultural exports (see point 4 below).</p>

<p>
	Real gross domestic income (GDI)—an alternative measure of output—increased 5.2 percent at an annual rate in the third quarter. (In theory, GDP and GDI should be equal, but in practice they usually differ because they use different data sources and methods.) The average of real GDP and real GDI, which CEA refers to as real gross domestic output (GDO), increased 4.2 percent at an annual rate in the third quarter. CEA research suggests that GDO is a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/docs/gdo_issue_brief_final.pdf">better measure</a> of economic activity than GDP (though not typically stronger or weaker).</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Real GDP and GDO Growth, 2007-2016" height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/chart1_GDP_growthgdpgdo.png" width="910" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>2. Third-quarter real GDP growth was revised up 0.3 percentage point at an annual rate. </strong>The upward revision to GDP growth was more than fully accounted for by upward revisions to consumer spending and structures investment, with smaller offsetting revisions in equipment investment, intellectual property investment, and inventory investment. The overall contour of third-quarter growth was little changed from last month’s advance estimate, though the 0.5-percentage-point upward revision to private domestic final purchases (the sum of consumption and fixed investment, see point 5 below) suggests greater momentum for growth in the fourth quarter of 2016.</p>

<p>
	In addition to reporting its first estimate of third-quarter GDI and GDO in today’s release, BEA also revised up its estimate of real GDI growth in the second quarter of 2016 from -0.2 percent to 0.7 percent due to an upward revision to wages and salaries. This boosted second-quarter real GDO growth to 1.1 percent, a stronger pace than the previously reported 0.6 percent.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Revisions to Real GDP Growth in 2016:Q3" height="810" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/chart2_GDP_gdprevisions.png" width="1616" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>3. Strong consumer spending growth in recent quarters has been supported in part by improvements in household balance sheets, with household debt service as a share of disposable income at a historically low level. </strong>Consumer spending contributed 1.9 percentage points to total real GDP growth in the third quarter, with 0.8 percentage point attributable to durable goods spending. In recent years, durable goods spending has contributed disproportionately to consumer spending growth: although durable goods spending makes up only about one-tenth of total consumer spending, it has been responsible for about one-quarter of the growth in consumer spending since the beginning of 2014. This strength in part reflects improvements in household balance sheets since the recession, as spending on durables tends to be more sensitive to financial conditions than other types of consumer expenditures. As the chart below shows, household debt service—the fraction of disposable income that households must spend on interest and principal payments for their outstanding debt—has fallen sharply in recent years, driven both by low interest rates and by sharp reductions in the level of outstanding household debt, and is now close to its lowest level on record (with data going back to 1980). This improvement in balance sheets has left households with more disposable income available for consumer purchases, and—along with <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/09/29/third-estimate-gross-domestic-product-second-quarter-2016">increases in real incomes</a>—has helped to support strong consumer spending growth.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Household Debt Service, 1990-2016" height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/chart3_GDP_housedebt.png" width="910" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>4. In part due to transitory factors, real exports contributed 1.2 percentage point to overall real GDP growth—their largest quarterly contribution since 2013—with goods exports providing the majority of the contribution. </strong>Exports of goods contributed 1.1 percentage point to overall real GDP growth in the third quarter, in part due to an unusually large increase in agricultural exports. Goods exports make up about two-thirds of total U.S. exports (with agricultural exports comprising around 5 percent of total exports) and the United States is the second-largest exporter of goods in the world according to <a href="http://stat.wto.org/Home/WSDBHome.aspx?Language=E" target="_blank">data from the World Trade Organization</a> (WTO). Although services exports have contributed less to overall GDP growth than goods exports in recent years, the <em>level</em> of U.S. services exports is high: according to WTO data, the United States is the world’s largest exporter of services, and the International Trade Administration (ITA) <a href="http://www.trade.gov/mas/ian/build/groups/public/@tg_ian/documents/webcontent/tg_ian_005506.pdf" target="_blank">estimates</a> that U.S. services exports support 4.8 million American jobs. Additionally, the division of exports into goods and services in today’s BEA release is based on final sales, and does not account for the value added by the services sector in each stage of the production process for export goods. ITA analysis finds that <a href="http://www.trade.gov/mas/ian/build/groups/public/@tg_ian/documents/webcontent/tg_ian_005506.pdf" target="_blank">nearly half</a> of the 6.8 million jobs supported by goods exports in 2014 were in the services sector.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Contribution of Exports to Real GDP Growth, 2007-2016" height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/chart4_GDP_exportcontribution.png" width="911" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>5. Real private domestic final purchases (PDFP)—the sum of consumption and fixed investment—rose 2.1 percent at an annual rate in the third quarter. </strong>PDFP—which excludes more volatile components of GDP like net exports and inventory investment, as well as government spending—is generally a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/02/27/second-estimate-gdp-fourth-quarter-2014#pdfp">more reliable indicator of next-quarter GDP growth than current GDP</a>. In the third quarter, the divergence between overall real GDP growth and the relatively weaker contribution of PDFP to growth was largely accounted for by the large positive contributions of inventory investment and exports to real GDP growth. Overall, PDFP rose 2.0 percent over the past four quarters; this is above the pace of real GDP growth over the same period, as inventory investment has subtracted 0.4 percentage point from growth over the past four quarters.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Real Private Domestic Final Purchases Growth, 2007-2016" height="661" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/chart5_GDP_pdfprgrowth.png" width="910" /></p>

<p>
	<em>As the Administration stresses every quarter, GDP figures can be volatile and are subject to substantial revision. Therefore, it is important not to read too much into any single report, and it is informative to consider each report in the context of other data as they become available.</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/jason-furman&quot;&gt;Jason Furman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More than 5.91 Million Records Released</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/28/more-591-million-records-released</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	In September 2009, the President announced that—for the first time in history—White House visitor records would be made available to the public on an ongoing basis. Today, the White House releases visitor records that were generated in August 2016. This release brings the total number of records made public by this White House to more than 5.91 million—all of which can be viewed in our <a href="/briefing-room/disclosures/visitor-records">Disclosures section</a>.</p>

<p class="rteright">
	<iframe class="socrata-embed"  src="https://open.whitehouse.gov/w/p86s-ychb/u9ea-ajcm?cur=zsf3oBqAbAA&amp;amp;from=root" height="600" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/amanda-stone&quot;&gt;Amanda Stone&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-310891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&amp;#039;s Celebrate Our Small Businesses</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/26/lets-celebrate-our-small-businesses</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="President Barack Obama, with daughters Malia and Sasha, shop for books at Upshur Street Books in Washington, D.C., on Small Business Saturday, Nov. 28, 2015.  (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)" height="1920" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/P112815PS-0038.jpg" width="2880" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 2880px;">
		President Barack Obama, with daughters Malia and Sasha, shop for books at Upshur Street Books in Washington, D.C., on Small Business Saturday, Nov. 28, 2015.&nbsp;<br />
		(Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	Today, on Small Business Saturday, we celebrate the contributions of small businesses to our country and our communities – and we encourage everyone to <a href="https://www.sba.gov/about-sba/sba-initiatives/small-business-saturday">make a visit to a small business</a> as part of their holiday shopping. It is well worth it. For the last eight years, I have had the honor of working with small business owners across the United States and have seen firsthand as they turn their dreams into engines of our economy and essential parts of our communities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	There’s plenty of reason for celebration today.&nbsp;</p>

<p>
	Through hard work and talent, small business owners have grown and created opportunity for Americans from coast to coast, contributing to the more than 15 million private-sector jobs created since early 2010.</p>

<p>
	Small business owners have helped to lead the way with higher minimum wages and pay --&nbsp;recognizing that when employees have the support they need to thrive, so do their businesses.</p>

<p>
	Under President Obama, small businesses have played a greater role than ever before in supporting the work of the federal government. In Fiscal Year 2015, for instance, we awarded an all-time high of more than a quarter of eligible federal contracts to small businesses, and we made great strides in ensuring more government contracts are given to women-owned small businesses -- nearly $18 billion worth.</p>

<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="President Barack Obama and daughters Sasha and Malia shop for books at Politics and Prose in Washington, D.C., on Small Business Saturday, Nov. 29, 2014. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)" height="1920" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/16786903841_3b1d5dca8a_b.jpg" width="2880" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 2880px;">
		President Barack Obama and daughters Sasha and Malia shop for books at Politics and Prose in Washington, D.C., on Small Business Saturday, Nov. 29, 2014. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	Perhaps most importantly, small businesses are the backbone of our communities. Small business owners don’t just employ our neighbors; more often than not, they live alongside us, too. They support our Little League teams, our schools, our houses of worship, and our charities. And they provide the essential character of towns and cities across America.</p>

<p>
	Dreams do not often materialize easily. It takes persistence, determination, and the ability to bounce back quickly from failure. Yet every day, small business owners across the United States defy the odds --&nbsp;never giving up, trusting their instincts, and following their dreams relentlessly. And we are all better for it.</p>

<p>
	So today, please join me in <a href="https://www.sba.gov/about-sba/sba-initiatives/small-business-saturday">supporting a small business in your community</a>&nbsp;--&nbsp;and saying thank you to all the men and women who have taken the leap of faith to realize their own entrepreneurial dreams.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/valerie-jarrett&quot;&gt;Valerie Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-311006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Address: Coming Together On Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/24/weekly-address-coming-together-thanksgiving</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	In this week&#039;s address, President Obama wished the American people a happy Thanksgiving. Thanksgiving reminds us that no matter our differences, we are still one people, part of something bigger than ourselves. Because what makes us American are the ideals to which we pledge our allegiance. And it&#039;s about our ability to live up to the creed "E Pluribus Unum" -- that out of many, we are one.</p>

<p>
	In case you missed it, be sure to take a look at the <a href="/blog/2016/11/22/president-obama-final-turkey-pardon">President&#039;s final pardoning of the National Thanksgiving Turkey</a>.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uIZDdnyMYr0?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	<a href="/the-press-office/2016/11/24/weekly-address-coming-together-thanksgiving">Transcript</a> | <a href="/videos/2016/November/20161124_Weekly_Address_HD.mp4">mp4</a> | <a href="/videos/2016/November/20161124_Weekly_Address.mp3">mp3</a></p>

<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/amanda-stone&quot;&gt;Amanda Stone&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-310981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Obama&amp;#039;s Final Turkey Pardon</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/22/president-obama-final-turkey-pardon</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="image-center">
	<figure class="image-captioned">
		<img alt="President Barack Obama and nephews Austin and Aaron Robinson watch the National Thanksgiving Turkey, Tater, flap during the pardon of the National Thanksgiving Turkey ceremony in the Rose Garden of the White House, Nov. 23, 2016" height="613" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/P112316CK-0208.jpg" width="920" />
		<figcaption style="max-width: 920px;">
			President Barack Obama and nephews Austin and Aaron Robinson watch the National Thanksgiving Turkey, Tater, flap during the pardon of the National Thanksgiving Turkey ceremony in the Rose Garden of the White House, Nov. 23, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)</figcaption>
	</figure>
</div>

<blockquote class="blockquote-2">
	Tomorrow is one of the best days of the year to be an American. It’s a day to count our blessings, spend time with the ones we love, and enjoy some good food and some great company. But it’s also one of the worst days of the year to be a turkey. They don’t have it so good.
	<div class="citation">
		President Barack Obama</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	This Thursday, friends and families across the United States will gather to give thanks, spend time with loved ones and enjoy a festive meal. But before the&nbsp;First Family sits down to their Thanksgiving dinner, President Obama will continue a long-cherished White House tradition and pardon the final turkey of his presidency.</p>

<p>
	Since 1947, the chairman of the National Turkey Federation has presented a turkey to the President of the United States, who grants a pardon to the bird.</p>

<p>
	While only one can be named the National Thanksgiving Turkey, both lucky birds will be sent to their new home at Virginia Tech where they will be cared for by veterinarians and students of Virginia Tech’s Animal and Poultry Sciences Department at “Gobbler&#039;s Rest” in Blacksburg, Virginia.</p>

<p>
	<strong>Tune in here to watch the official pardoning ceremony.</strong></p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xzzNdZ28Kjk?rel=0&cc_load_policy=1&version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<blockquote class="blockquote-1">
	And it is my great privilege -- well, it’s my privilege -- actually, let’s just say it’s my job -- to grant them clemency this afternoon. As I do, I want to take a moment to recognize the brave turkeys who weren’t so lucky, who didn’t get to ride the gravy train to freedom -- who met their fate with courage and sacrifice -- and proved that they weren’t chicken.
	<div class="citation">
		President Obama, November 23, 2016</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	<br />
	<strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/11/23/remarks-president-pardoning-national-thanksgiving-turkey" target="_blank">Read the President&#039;s remarks, including many more&nbsp;Thanksgiving Day puns,&nbsp;here.&nbsp;</a></strong></p>

<p>
	Which turkey will take home this year&#039;s title? Per a recent digital tradition, <a href="https://twitter.com/WhiteHouse/status/801117443318026240" target="_blank"><strong>you can vote for your favorite on social media</strong></a>. Meet this year&#039;s contenders: Tater and Tot!</p>

<p>
	<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center" data-width="550"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Who will receive this year’s <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WHTurkeyPardon?src=hash">#WHTurkeyPardon</a>? Vote before the official ceremony tomorrow: <a href="https://t.co/wTcdWKlWAM">https://t.co/wTcdWKlWAM</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TeamTater?src=hash">#TeamTater</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TeamTot?src=hash">#TeamTot</a></p>&mdash; The White House (@WhiteHouse) <a href="https://twitter.com/WhiteHouse/status/801117443318026240">November 22, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>
	<img alt="tater" height="460" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/tater_920.jpg" width="920" />&nbsp;&nbsp;<img alt="Tot" height="460" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/tot_920.jpg" width="920" /></p>

<h3 class="light">
	A look back: President Obama&#039;s turkey pardons</h3>

<p>
	President Obama has had the honor of pardoning multiple birds. In case you missed the previous years, here&#039;s a look back:</p>

<p>
	<strong>2009</strong> - The President officially pardoned <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2009/11/25/official-pardoning-turkey" target="_blank">not one but two turkeys</a>, sparing both “Courage” and “Carolina” at the request of his compassionate daughters, Sasha and Malia and starting a new tradition.</p>

<p>
	<strong>2010</strong> - After a rigorous competition to win the presidential pardon at home on Foster Farms Wellsford Ranch near Modesto, California, President Obama pardoned both <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2010/11/24/pardoning-national-thanksgiving-turkey">Apple and his understudy Cider</a>. Both turkeys were then sent to live out their days at Mount Vernon, home of our nation’s first President George Washington.</p>

<p>
	<strong>2011</strong> - President Obama <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/11/23/president-obama-pardons-peace-liberty-turkeys-0">pardoned turkeys Peace and Liberty</a> on the North Portico of the White House.</p>

<p>
	<strong>2012 </strong> - This year marked the 65th anniversary of the National Turkey presentation and the first time the American people cast their vote via the White House Facebook page to decide which of two turkeys would receive the honor. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/11/21/president-obama-pardons-cobbler-national-thanksgiving-turkey">Cobbler won the title of National Thanksgiving Turkey</a>, but both he and his alternate, Gobbler, received the official pardon.</p>

<p>
	<strong>2013</strong> - This year, White House digital audiences could vote on Twitter, Facebook or Instagram for <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2013/11/26/gobble-help-choose-2013-national-thanksgiving-turkey">Caramel or Popcorn</a>.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/hL-YYsQiqg/" target="_blank"><img alt="Caramel and Popcorn Instagram video" height="603" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/Turkeys_IG_screenshot_2013.png" width="522" /></a></p>

<p>
	<strong>2014</strong> - The American people were graced with the opportunity<a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2014/11/26/president-obama-pardons-thanksgiving-turkey"> to meet Mac and Cheese</a>. Cheese was ultimately voted the&nbsp;2014 National Thanksgiving Turkey.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="" height="521" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Capture1_0.PNG" width="623" /></p>

<p>
	<strong>2015</strong> - Last year, <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/11/24/taking-home-title-who-will-be-years-national-thanksgiving-turkey">we were introduced to Honest &amp; Abe</a>, two twin male turkeys. While their love for country music made them a stand out, both turkeys were fortunate enough to be pardoned by President Obama.</p>

<p class="image-center">
	<img alt="Vote 2015" height="330" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/2015_turkey_tweet.png" width="498" /></p>

<div class="image-center">
	<figure class="image-captioned">
		<img alt="President Barack Obama and daughters Sasha and Malia participate in the annual National Thanksgiving Turkey pardon ceremony in the Rose Garden of the White House, Nov. 25, 2015. National Turkey Federation Chairman Jihad Douglas participates. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/TurkeyPardon_2015.jpeg" />
		<figcaption>
			President Barack Obama and daughters Sasha and Malia participate in the annual National Thanksgiving Turkey pardon ceremony in the Rose Garden of the White House, Nov. 25, 2015. National Turkey Federation Chairman Jihad Douglas participates. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)</figcaption>
	</figure>
</div>

<p>
	<br />
	<strong>Happy Thanksgiving!</strong></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 10:03:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/author/amanda-stone&quot;&gt;Amanda Stone&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-310746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obama Administration Marks Five Years of the Veterans Opportunity to Work to Hire Heroes Act</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/21/obama-administration-marks-five-years-veterans-opportunity-work-hire-heroes-act</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<figure class="image-captioned">
	<img alt="President Barack Obama shakes the hand of Donald E. Larson, National President of the Fleet Reserve Association, after delivering remarks during a Veterans Day ceremony at the Memorial Amphitheater at Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington, Virginia, Nov. 11, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)" height="613" src="/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/images/Blog/P111116PS-0503.jpg" width="920" />
	<figcaption style="max-width: 920px;">
		President Barack Obama shakes the hand of Donald E. Larson, National President of the Fleet Reserve Association, after delivering remarks during a Veterans Day ceremony at the Memorial Amphitheater at Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington, Virginia, Nov. 11, 2016. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
	Five years ago today, President Obama signed into law the Veterans Opportunity to Work (VOW) to Hire Heroes Act of 2011, which brought about major changes to help transitioning Service members and veterans.</p>

<p>
	On the fifth anniversary of the signing of the law, we pause to reflect on the progress the Administration has made to promote the economic opportunity of our service members and veterans.</p>

<p>
	In 2011, faced with veteran unemployment rates that remained high following the Great Recession and a national need for more entrepreneurs and skilled workers, the President signed the VOW Act, which mandated that the Department of Labor (DOL) study the skills that service members learn in the military and improve the translation of those skills into civilian-sector certifications. The Act also authorized the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide eligible veterans with up to one year of additional Montgomery GI Bill benefits, to extend vocational rehabilitation and employment benefits for 12 months for eligible veterans, and to expand the Special Incentive Program to employers who hire and provide on-the-job training for eligible Veterans.</p>

<p>
	At the same time, the Administration brought together a diverse group of government partners charged with redesigning the decades old Transition Assistance Program (TAP) to ensure separating service members are prepared for educational advancement and meaningful career opportunities after transitioning into civilian life.</p>

<p>
	Together, the Departments of Defense (DoD), Education, DOL, and VA, as well as the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) and the Small Business Administration (SBA), and others, oversaw the creation and implementation of a framework to instruct, gauge, and enhance service member career readiness through the redesigned TAP.</p>

<p>
	The interagency collaboration improved communication on the topic; better leveraged federal tools, processes, and limited resources; and resulted in several enhancements to the transition process, including the following:</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		A redesigned curriculum that is mandatory for all separating service members and available to all military spouses</li>
	<li>
		Additional “career tracks” for those wanting to start a business, seeking job-ready skills, and those pursuing higher education</li>
	<li>
		Smaller class sizes to provide individual attention</li>
	<li>
		Individual transition plans that are customized to each Service member’s personal goals</li>
	<li>
		Completion based on achieving "Career Readiness Standards,” not simply attendance</li>
</ul>

<p>
	The program concludes with a capstone event, verifying that each service member has met Career Readiness Standards and has an actionable individual transition plan.</p>

<p>
	The enhanced TAP also equips service members with skills and resources to cope with the stress of separating from the military; how to identify and promote translatable employment skills, training and pre-transition activities to help them obtain meaningful civilian employment; and information on how to capitalize on all the VA benefits earned through their military service. An additional congressional authority called SkillBridge complements TAP by allowing eligible service members to obtain civilian job skills training from employers beginning up to six months prior to separating from the military.</p>

<p>
	Watch service members discuss their experience going through the program.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CHRNw1eT-dU?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	To further improve transition, an online curriculum was made available to service members, veterans, and their families. Participants can access the courses and review the training at their preferred pace. Veterans who transitioned before the enactment of the redesigned TAP can also take advantage of this online curriculum at any time. <a href="http://jko.jten.mil/courses/tap/TGPS%20Standalone%20Training/start.html" target="_blank">This curriculum is available here</a>.</p>

<p>
	Since the implementation of the VOW Act:</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		More than 1 million service members have transitioned into civilian life</li>
	<li>
		The unemployment rate for veterans has been reduced by more than half, falling from a high of 9.9 percent in 2011 to 4.3 percent today. In addition, the Post-9/11 veterans unemployment rate is 4.7 percent today, down from a high of 15.2 percent in 2011</li>
	<li>
		VA has deployed more than 300 Benefit Advisors worldwide to provide information on the benefits and services VA provides</li>
</ul>

<p>
	Every year, roughly 200,000 service members separate, retire, or are released from active duty, and we are excited about the progress that has been made in preparing them for success. Moving forward, agencies will continue to work to ensure service members, veterans, and their family members are provided the opportunity to fulfill the American dream.</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		To learn more about DoD’s curriculum and transition resources, visit: <a href="https://www.dodtap.mil/">https://www.dodtap.mil/</a></li>
	<li>
		To learn more about VA support under TAP, visit: <a href="http://www.benefits.va.gov/tap/">http://www.benefits.va.gov/tap/</a></li>
	<li>
		To learn more about DOL’s employment resources for veterans and more than 2,400 local American Job Centers across the country offering in-person assistance, visit: <a href="http://veterans.gov/">http://veterans.gov/</a></li>
	<li>
		To learn more about OPM’s resources supporting the employment of veterans in the federal government, visit Feds Hire Vets: <a href="https://www.fedshirevets.gov/">https://www.fedshirevets.gov/</a></li>
</ul>

<p>
	To learn more about the Federal Government&#039;s Council on Veterans Employment efforts to assist veterans, transitioning service members, and their families with federal careers, visit Feds Hire Vets, the federal government&#039;s one-stop resource for federal employment information at: <a href="http://www.fedshirevets.gov">www.fedshirevets.gov</a>.</p>

<p>
	<em>Ayotunde Babajide&nbsp;is&nbsp;Senior Policy Advisor for the National Economic Council and the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 10:06:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ayotunde Babajide</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-310751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Wing Week 11/18/16 or, &amp;quot;A Community of Nations&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/11/19/west-wing-week-111816-or-community-nations</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	From honoring our veterans at the Arlington National Cemetery, to the President&#039;s final trip abroad, it’s been a busy week. Watch behind the scenes footage and highlights from his tour of Greece, Germany and Peru&nbsp;by watching this week&#039;s episode of&nbsp;West Wing Week narrated by Press Secretary Josh Earnest.</p>

<p>
	<div class="youtube-shortcode-container--responsive youtube-shortcode-lg "><iframe width="100%" height="100%" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Dxg0Dr_Kcpc?version=3" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>
	<strong><em>Learn more about the events featured in this week&#039;s episode below.</em></strong></p>

<p>
	Friday, November 11, 2016 – <a href="https://twitter.com/WhiteHouse/status/797193434675060736" target="_blank">President Obama pays tribute to our nations veterans at Arlington National Cemetery</a></p>

<p>
	Monday, November 14, 2016 – <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O4iWqCH9EVE" target="_blank">President Obama takes questions in Brady Press Briefing Room </a></p>

<p>
	Monday, November 14, 2016 - <a href="https://medium.com/the-white-house/the-president-abroad-a-look-ahead-at-greece-germany-and-peru-265b9c00a94e" target="_blank">President Obama begins his final foreign travel journey as President</a></p>

<p>
	Tuesday, November 15, 2016 – <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DkCQLEKnxTg" target="_blank">President Obama meets with President Pavlopoulos </a></p>

<p>
	Tuesday, November 15, 2016 - <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZzmEl5sj6SU" target="_blank">President Obama meets with Prime Minister Tsipras of Greece</a></p>

<p>
	Wednesday, November 16, 2016 – <a href="https://medium.com/the-white-house/behind-the-scenes-president-obama-visits-the-acropolis-in-athens-greece-190d048daa8f" target="_blank">President Obama tours ancient Acropolis and Parthenon</a></p>

<p>
	Thursday, November 17, 2016 – <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BM7lNvXhFYT/?taken-by=whitehouse" target="_blank">President Obama meets with Chancellor Angela Merkel in Berlin, Germany</a></p>

<p>
	<em>Crystal Miller is a intern in the Office of Digital Strategy</em></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 09:46:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Crystal Miller </dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">whr-310571</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>